<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Path of Instinct Barbarian</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="barbarian-instinct.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/barbarian-instinct.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Path of Instinct" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT">
        <supports>Primal Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While many Barbarians lose control when they rage, flying into wild tantrums, some operate in a state of cold absolute focus, becoming creatures of pure instinct and finely honed reflexes. Entering a void-like state of mind, they act almost without conscious thought, accomplishing superhuman feats and shrugging off hits.</p>
            <p class="indent">Though utter calm might seem less frightening than the frothing rage of their counterparts, true terror sets in once their foes witness the destruction such perfect focus can bring.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_FOCUSED_RAGE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCTIVE_INSIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_BLIND_FIGHTING" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_INSTINCTIVE_STRIKE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_FOCUSED_RAGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCTIVE_INSIGHT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_BLIND_FIGHTING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_EVASION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_INSTINCTIVE_STRIKE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Focused Rage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_FOCUSED_RAGE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, your rage becomes a state of pure focus. You can perform impossible feats in this state of extreme focus by expending focus dice. When you enter a rage, you gain a number of d8 focus dice equal to your proficiency bonus. Any unspent dice are lost when your rage ends. You can expend these dice on the following abilities:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Perfect Dodge.</strong> When you make a Dexterity saving throw or Dexterity ability check, you can expend one focus die, expending it and adding to the roll. You can do this after rolling the d20, but before the outcome is determined.</li>
                <li><strong>Perfect Intuition.</strong> When you make a Wisdom saving throw or ability check, you can expend one focus die to add it to the roll. When you do this with the Search action, you can take the Search action as a bonus action instead of an action.</li>
                <li><strong>Perfect Parry.</strong> When another creature damages you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction and expend one focus die to reduce this damage by the number you roll on your focus die + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</li>
                <li><strong>Perfect Strike.</strong> When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one focus die to add it to the roll. You can use this ability after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</li>
                <li><strong>Perfect Focus.</strong> If your rage would end for any reason other than being knocked unconscious, you can expend one focus die to prevent it from ending until the start of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Rage">
            <description>When you enter a rage, you gain {{proficiency}}d8 focus dice. Any unspent dice are lost when your rage ends. You can expend these dice on the following abilities:
            Perfect Dodge. When you make a Dexterity saving throw or Dexterity ability check, you can expend one focus die, expending it and adding to the roll. You can do this after rolling the d20, but before the outcome is determined.
            Perfect Intuition. When you make a Wisdom saving throw or ability check, you can expend one focus die to add it to the roll. When you do this with the Search action, you can take the Search action as a bonus action instead of an action.
            Perfect Parry. When another creature damages you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction and expend one focus die to reduce this damage by the number you roll on your focus die + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).
            Perfect Strike. When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one focus die to add it to the roll. You can use this ability after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.
            Perfect Focus. If your rage would end for any reason other than being knocked unconscious, you can expend one focus die to prevent it from ending until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Instinctive Insight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCTIVE_INSIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 3rd level, your natural intuition and ability to read creature behavior grants you proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in Insight, you gain expertise in it, allowing you to add twice your proficiency bonus to Insight checks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INSIGHT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Blind Fighting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, your senses are so sharp that you gain an instinctive blindsight of 10 feet while raging. The range of this blind sight increases by 10 feet at 10th level (to 20 feet), and again at 14th level (to 30 feet).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain an instinctive blindsight of 10 feet while raging. </description>
            <description level="10">You gain an instinctive blindsight of 20 feet while raging. </description>
            <description level="14">You gain an instinctive blindsight of 30 feet while raging. </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_EVASION">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as an ancient red dragon’s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Instinctive Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_INSTINCT_INSTINCTIVE_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, when a creature ends their turn within range of your blindsight while you are raging, you can expend one focus die as a reaction to move toward that creature (up to your movement speed). If you can reach the creature after your movement, you can make one weapon attack against them as part of this reaction. This movement does not trigger opportunity attacks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature ends their turn within range of your blindsight while you are raging, you can expend one focus die as a reaction to move toward that creature (up to your movement speed). If you can reach the creature after your movement, you can make one weapon attack against them as part of this reaction. This movement does not trigger opportunity attacks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>