<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Psion</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-psion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/class-psion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Psion" type="Class" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_PSION">
        <description>
            <p>Psions are those who have tapped into a special otherworldly force, with the ability to actualize the power of their mind to accomplish impossible feats. Reading minds, lifting vast weights, and transcending physical limitations, they tend to inspire awe and terror in equal measure.</p>
            <p class="indent">The exact nature of what psionic power is might be a question answered in your setting, or it might not be. Most view psionic power as coming from within, though other answers exist—anything from the leaking power of the realms beyond, to an alternate way to express magic, to an actualization of an individual’s will upon the world.</p>
            <h4>Powerful Minds</h4>
            <p>Since a psion’s weapon is their mind, they are always a careless thought away from harming those around them. For a psion, the line between thinking and doing can be very thin, forcing them to keep their thoughts and emotions in check, lest their powers run amok. This leads to many of them developing odd behaviors or mannerisms to help them control their state of mind, frequently seeming quite eccentric to an outside observer.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider how your psion keeps their powers in check, and how much their power bleeds into their everyday life. How reading minds may affect their body language or habits. Do they add wood to the campfire from the comfort of their bedroll, or do they restrain themselves from using their power for trivial matters lest they slip up?</p>
            <h4>Misunderstood Powers</h4>
            <p>In a world of widespread magic, many will assume a psion to be a type of Sorcerer or Wizard, mistaking their powers for the common applications of magic. The common villager keeps only one mental category for the supernatural and creepy people that bend reality to their will. But even among magic users, a psion’s powers will frequently be found unnerving.</p>
            <p class="indent">It is often those who do understand magic that find a psion’s abilities the most aberrant. A force that intersects the magical weave rather than obeys it, the nature of the power that the psion wields one can only contemplate with unease.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A PSION</h4>
            <p>When creating a psion, consider your character’s background. How did you become a psion? Were you born with latent powers? Or did something happen to you granting your powers? Or did you intentionally train yourself through rigorous mental exercise to leverage them? Consider how developing a rare and mysterious power would have affected your interactions with people.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider what your purpose is with your newfound powers, or how you plan to use your powers. Do you intend to be taken for a Wizard casting magic, or are you freely open about being of a... different nature?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a psion quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Intelligence your highest ability score, followed by Dexterity or Constitution. Second, choose a background that lends itself to intelligence skills.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an psion, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 10d6 per psion level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per psion level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> </li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Psionics, and choose two from Deception, History, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, or Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff, (b) a dagger, or (c) a martial weapon (if proficient)</li>
                <li>(a) leather armor or (b) scale mail (if proficient)</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
            <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE PSION</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Psi Points</td><td class="col-10">Psi Limit</td><td class="col-10">Psi Talent</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype, Psionics</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Psionic Talents</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Secondary Discipline, Psionic Archetype feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Psionic Mastery</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td class="left">—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>9</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td class="left">—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>11</td><td>6</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (6th level)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>13</td><td>7</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (7th level)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>14</td><td>7</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype feature </td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>15</td><td>8</td><td>7</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (8th level)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>16</td><td>8</td><td>7</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>17</td><td>9</td><td>7</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (9th level)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>18</td><td>9</td><td>8</td><td class="left">Third Discipline</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>19</td><td>10</td><td>8</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>20</td><td>10</td><td>8</td><td class="left">Ascension</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASI" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skills, Psion" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASI" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
            <list>Psionic</list>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionic Archetype" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you pick the archetype of psion you embody, choosing from Awakened Mind, Unleashed Mind, Transcended Mind, Shaper’s Mind, Wandering Mind, Elemental Mind or Consuming Mind, each of which are detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level, and again at 3rd, 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" supports="Psionic-Archetype" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionics" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS">
        <description>
            <h5>Psionic Disciplines</h5>
            <p>You are granted access to a psionic discipline (such as Telepathy or Telekinesis) by your chosen archetype. A psionic discipline comes with a passive feature that expands your character’s capabilities and an active psionic power that can be modified and empowered with psi points. Additionally you can use your discipline in more detailed applications to recreate the effect of certain spells, listed at the end of the discipline description. At 3rd level you can select a second discipline, and 18th level you can select a 3rd discipline.</p>
            <p class="indent">Psionic powers are suppressed by antimagic fields and can be dispelled with dispel magic, but are only affected by counterspell if recreating the effect of a spell. Any check required to dispel magic, counterspell or to identify a spell being cast with psionics is made with disadvantage unless the caster also has the Psionics feature. The detect magic spell will detect the usage of psionics, but not their nature: it will show up as a mysterious untyped power, even if being used to generate the effect of a spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">When recreating a spell through a psionic effect (using a psionic discipline to cast the spell) the spell has no material or verbal components, but using any psionic ability requires somatic components and causes the psion to vibrantly glow with the otherworldly psionic energies they are controlling.</p>
            <h5>Psi Points</h5>
            <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain access to psi points used to fuel psionic discipline powers and effects. You have a number of psi points equal to your psion level, and you regain all spent points when you finish a short or long rest. You can spend a number of psi points equal to half your Psion level (rounded up) at a time. For example, if you’re a 5th-level Psion, you can spend 3 psi points on a psionic power or cast a spell with a cost of 3 psi points.</p>
            <h5>Psionic Ability</h5>
            <p></p>
            <center>
                <p><strong>Psionic save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p><strong>Psionic attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            </center>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{psi-points:count}} Psi Points and your Psi limit is {{psi-points:max}} and restore on short rest.
            When recreating a spell through a psionic effect (using a psionic discipline to cast the spell) the spell has no material or verbal components, but using any psionic ability requires somatic components and causes the psion to vibrantly glow.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="psi-points:count" value="level:psion" />
            <stat name="psi-points:max" value="level:psion:half:up" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionic Talents" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you gain access to a psionic talent allowing you to further specialize. Pick two talents from the list of psionic talents presented at the end of the class description. You can pick a new psionic talent at 5th, 7th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th level. When you level up, you can replace a psionic talent you have previously selected with a different option.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You may replace a talent when you level up.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talents 1" supports="psionic-talent"  number="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Second Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 3rd level, you can select a second psionic discipline from the list of psionic disciplines. You can’t select a Discipline you already know. You gain all features of a psionic discipline when selecting it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>            
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Second Discipline" supports="psionic-discipline" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASI">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,4" level="4"/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,8" level="8"/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,12" level="12"/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,16" level="16"/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,19" level="19"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionic Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 5th level, you gain mastery of your psionic powers. At the start of your turn you get 1 free psi point. This can be spent to empower psionic disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. If you have any unspent free psi points granted by this feature left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 11th level, this is increased to 2 free psi points, and at 17th level, this is increased to 3. Points can be split between different abilities.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> At the start of your turn you get 1 free psi point. This can be spent to empower psionic disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. Points are lost at the end of your turn.</description>
            <description level="11"> At the start of your turn you get 2 free psi points. This can be spent to empower psionic disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. Points are lost at the end of your turn.</description>
            <description level="17"> At the start of your turn you get 3 free psi points. This can be spent to empower psionic disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. Points are lost at the end of your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Innate Psionics" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you gain the ability to exert great feats of psionic power. Choose one 6th-level spell from the psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast that spell once. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again. At higher levels, you gain more innate abilities of your choice that can be used in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Innate Psionics when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>Choose one 6th-level spell from the psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast that spell once.
            Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</description>
            <description level="13">Choose one 6th-level and one 7th-level spell from the psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast that spell once.
            Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</description>
            <description level="15">Choose one 6th-level, one 7th-level, and one 8th-level spell from the psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast that spell once.
            Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</description>
            <description level="17">Choose one 6th-level, one 7th-level, one 8th-level, and one 9th-level spell from the psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast that spell once.
            Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Third Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 18th level, you can select a third psionic discipline from the list of psionic disciplines. You can’t select a discipline you already know. You gain all features of a psionic discipline when selecting it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>            
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Third Discipline" supports="psionic-discipline" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ascension" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 20th level, if you die you can choose to become an incorporeal entity on the Border Ethereal at the spot you died in the Material Plane at the start of your next turn. This entity has the physical ability scores (Strength, Dexterity, Constitution) and abilities of a ghost, but has your mental ability scores (Intelligence, Wisdom, Charisma) and your psion class abilities.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you take this form your current and maximum hit points becomes that of the ghost while you are in the form, if you have less than 10 psi points when you would assume this form, you have 10 psi points. While in this form you can’t rest to regain spent abilities. If you exhaust all Psi Points or the ghost is destroyed, you die as a normal creature would.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you die you can choose to become an incorporeal entity on the Border Ethereal at the spot you died in the Material Plane at the start of your next turn. This entity has the physical ability scores and abilities of a ghost, but has your mental ability scores and your psion class abilities.
            When you take this form your current and maximum hit points becomes that of the ghost while you are in the form, if you have less than 10 psi points when you would assume this form, you have 10 psi points. While in this form you can’t rest to regain spent abilities. If you exhaust all Psi Points or the ghost is destroyed, you die as a normal creature would.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Psionic Disciplines -->

    <element name="Enhancement Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Enhancement is the ability to interact with a creature’s nature and abilities with your psionic power</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ENHANCING_SKILL" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_ENHANCING_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ENHANCING_SKILL" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_ENHANCING_SURGE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Enhancing Skill" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ENHANCING_SKILL">
        <description>
            <p>You can focus your psionics to enhance your abilities. Whenever you make a skill check using Strength or Dexterity, you can add 1d4 to the result.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you make a skill check using Strength or Dexterity, you can add 1d4 to the result.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Enhancing Surge" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_ENHANCING_SURGE">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You empower the body of a target creature you can see with your Psionics. The target gains 1d6 temporary hit points and the next time the target deals damage, it deals 1d6 additional damage to one application of that damage roll. Any remaining temporary hit points from this power fade when you use it again.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend Psi Points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Enhancing Surge (you can add multiple modifiers). The points must be spent when choosing the target of the power.</p>
            <p><strong>Fortifying</strong>(1+ psi point): The target gains an additional +1d6 temporary hit points for each point spent.</p>
            <p><strong>Resilient</strong>(3 psi points): the target gains resistance to all damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Savage</strong> (1+ psi point): The target's next weapon attack deals an +1d6 additional damage for each point spent.</p>            
            <p><strong>Swift</strong>(2 psi points): The target gains an additional action. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</p>
            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Enhancement)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Enhancement psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>heroism, longstrider, unlocked potential</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>alter self, enlarge/reduce, lesser restoration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>haste, protection from energy</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>freedom of movement, stoneskin</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>greater restoration, invested competency</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_UNLOCKED_POTENTIAL" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCCC_PSIONIC_INVESTED_COMPETENCY" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Body Control" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_BODY_CONTROL">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 5 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT,[level:psion:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot or psi points. Additionally, when you cast enlarge/reduce on yourself, you may expend 1 psi point instead of 2.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot or psi points. Additionally, when you cast enlarge/reduce on yourself, you may expend 1 psi point instead of 2.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Enhanced Regrowth" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_ENHANCED_REGROWTH">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the cure wounds spell, and can cast it as a 1st-level spell by expending 1 psi point. You can cast it at a higher level by spending an additional psi point for each level above first. When you cast cure wounds on a creature, you can use Enhancing Surge on that creature as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast cure wounds 1 psi point per level. When you cast cure wounds on a creature, you can use Enhancing Surge on that creature as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Metamorphosis" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_METAMORPHOSIS">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Prerequisite: Body Control</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT,ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_BODY_CONTROL</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The mutate and polymorph spells are added to your Enhancement Alternate Effects list.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can only target yourself when casting polymorph this way.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The mutate and polymorph spells are added to your Enhancement Alternate Effects list. You can only target yourself when casting polymorph this way.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_MUTATE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Physical Surge" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_PHYSICAL_SURGE">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you use Enhancing Surge targeting yourself, you can choose to make your Strength or Dexterity ability score equal to your Intelligence ability score until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use Enhancing Surge targeting yourself, you can choose to make your Strength or Dexterity ability score equal to your Intelligence ability score until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Surging Power" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_SURGING_POWER">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you target only yourself with Enhancing Surge, you can use the power as a bonus action instead of an action, but the damage and temporary hit points the base power grants are reduced to 1d4 when using the power this way.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you target only yourself with Enhancing Surge, you can use the power as a bonus action instead of an action, but the damage and temporary hit points the base power grants are reduced to 1d4 when using the power this way.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Transcendent Life" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TRANSCENDENT_LIFE">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 9 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT,[level:psion:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The mass cure wounds and reincarnate spells are added to your Enhancement Alternate Effects list. Reincarnate requires its normal material components when cast this way.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The mass cure wounds and reincarnate spells are added to your Enhancement Alternate Effects list. Reincarnate requires its normal material components when cast this way.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REINCARNATE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Projection Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Projection is the ability to project what is in your mind to the outside world with your psionic power.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECT_ITEM" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_ASTRAL_CONSTRUCT" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECT_ITEM" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_ASTRAL_CONSTRUCT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Project Item" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_PROJECT_ITEM">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can use your powers to project an inanimate object you imagine into your hands. It can’t be larger than 3 feet on any side or weigh more than 10 pounds, and is clearly ethereal in nature. The item behaves as a solid object. Weapons created with this feature deal force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Projected items fade after 1 minute, and you can have no more than 3 projected items at a time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you can use your powers to project an inanimate object you imagine into your hands. It can’t be larger than 3 feet on any side or weigh more than 10 pounds, and is clearly ethereal in nature. The item behaves as a solid object. Weapons created with this feature deal force damage.
            Projected items fade after 1 minute, and you can have no more than 3 projected items at a time.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Construct" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_ASTRAL_CONSTRUCT">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You project an ethereal creation from your mind at a space you can see within range, taking the shape of a Medium or smaller creature, weapon, or other object. This creation is clearly ethereal in nature. When you create it, and on subsequent turns using your action to mentally control it, you can move it up to 30 feet in any direction and attack, so long as it doesn’t move beyond the range of the power. To attack with it, make a melee spell attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 force damage. If the Astral Construct moves out of range of the spell, it fades away into nothing, ending the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the Astral Construct is active, you can spend psi points up to your per use limit to issue commands that affect and empower your construct. Commands require no action, but you can’t exceed your psi point limit in total commands issued, and each command can only be issued once per turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Grab</strong>(1 psi point): Can only be used while your construct is Solidified. A target creature within 5 feet of your construct that is no more than one size larger than the construct must make a Strength saving throw or become restrained by the construct. At the end of each of the restrained creature’s turns it can repeat the saving throw. The condition ends if the construct becomes ethereal again, or becomes more than one size smaller than the target.</p>
            <p><strong>Grow</strong>(1 psi point): Your construct increases by one size, and its number of damage dice increases by one. It returns to its normal size at the start of your next turn. It can only gain one additional die (for example, up to 2d8).</p>
            <p><strong>Relocate</strong> (1 psi point): The construct disappears and reappears anywhere within 60 feet of you.</p>            
            <p><strong>Replicate</strong>(3 psi points): You use Relocate, but the original doesn’t disappear. Until the end of your turn, you have another construct and control both with the same action (commands only affect one of your choice). Pick one construct to fade at the start of your next turn or use Sustain.</p>
            <p><strong>Solidify</strong>(1 psi point1): Your construct becomes solid, blocking its space until the start of your next turn. You can only use this command if it is in an unoccupied space. It has an armor class of 16 and hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier + your psion level. The construct becomes ethereal again if it drops to zero hit points.</p>
            <p><strong>Strike</strong>(2 psi points): The construct makes an attack (even if it has already attacked).</p>
            <p><strong>Sustain</strong>(1+ psi points): At the start of your turn, you can sustain the effect of a Solidify, Grow or Replicate command for an additional round. An effect that has been replicated can be sustained across all replicated constructs with a single use, but each effect can only be sustained once per turn (for example, you can never sustain more than one replicated construct). This costs 1 psi point for each effect sustained. Sustaining Solidify refreshes the construct’s hit points to its maximum.</p>
            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Projection)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Projection psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>floating disk, unseen servant</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>mirror image</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>phantom steed</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>arcane eye</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>creation</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TENSERS_FLOATING_DISK" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Animated Projection" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_ANIMATED_PROJECTION">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 10 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION,[level:psion:10]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You learn to project a swarm of ethereal objects. As an action, you can expend 5 psi points to cast animate objects. When cast in this way, the spell creates new ethereal objects rather than animating existing ones.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you can expend 5 psi points to cast animate objects. When cast in this way, the spell creates new ethereal objects rather than animating existing ones.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Swap" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_ASTRAL_SWAP">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can expend 1 psi point to swap places with your Astral Construct.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can expend 1 psi point to swap places with your Astral Construct.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Life Link" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_LIFE_LINK">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When a solidified construct takes damage, you can choose to take that damage instead of the construct (no action required). You have resistance to the damage taken.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a solidified construct takes damage, you can choose to take that damage instead of the construct (no action required). You have resistance to the damage taken.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Matter Made Real" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_MATTER_MADE_REAL">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 9 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION,[level:psion:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to solidify some of your projections into real objects. You can cast fabricate and wall of stone by expending psi points equal to the spell level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to solidify some of your projections into real objects. You can cast fabricate and wall of stone by expending psi points equal to the spell level.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Projected Weaponry" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_PROJECTED_WEAPONRY">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you project a weapon with your Project Item feature, it gains the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can project it as a bonus action and you can project up 3 weapons or pieces of ammunition at the same time.</li>
                <li>You are proficient with any projected weapon.</li>
                <li>It is no longer restricted to a maximum of 3 feet when it takes the form of a weapon (for a Medium-sized creature).</li>
                <li>You can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls with it.</li>
                <li> If it has the thrown property, its throwing range is doubled. If it doesn’t have the thrown property, it gains the thrown (10/30) property.</li>
                <li>You can apply the Astral Construct modifiers Grow and Sustain to Projected Weaponry. Grow adds 1d8 to the weapon’s damage dice. You can expend Psionic Mastery on these modifiers.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you project a weapon with your Project Item feature, it gains the following benefits:
            You can project it as a bonus action and you can project up 3 weapons or pieces of ammunition at the same time. 
            You are proficient with any projected weapon. 
            It is no longer restricted to a maximum of 3 feet when it takes the form of a weapon (for a Medium-sized creature). 
            You can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls with it. 
            If it has the thrown property, its throwing range is doubled. If it doesn’t have the thrown property, it gains the thrown (10/30) property. 
            You can apply the Astral Construct modifiers Grow and Sustain to Projected Weaponry. Grow adds 1d8 to the weapon’s damage dice. You can expend Psionic Mastery on these modifiers. </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unlimited Imagination" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_UNLIMITED_IMAGINATION">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Shaper's Mind</prerequisite>
<!-- Check this later, for shapers mind requiremen-->        
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you manifest a construct, you can select two options from Boundless Imagination.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you manifest a construct, you can select two options from Boundless Imagination.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Telekinesis Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Telekinesis is the ability to interact with physical objects and energy with your psionic powers.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINETIC_HANDS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_TELEKINETIC_FORCE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINETIC_HANDS" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_TELEKINETIC_FORCE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Telekinetic Hands" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINETIC_HANDS">
        <description>
            <p>When you gain this feature, you can manipulate small objects within 30 feet with your mind as if using your hand to interact with it. You can use this power to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can’t Attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds in this manner. You can move an item you are controlling in this way up to 30 feet during your turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend 1 or more psi points to increase how much you can move this way by 100 pounds per psi point spent for 1 turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can manipulate small objects within 30 feet with your mind as if using your hand to interact with it. You can use this power to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can’t Attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds in this manner. You can move an item you are controlling in this way up to 30 feet during your turn.
            You can spend 1 or more psi points to increase how much you can move this way by 100 pounds per psi point spent for 1 turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Telekinetic Force" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_TELEKINETIC_FORCE">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You smash a target creature or object you can see with your mental power. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or take 1d10 bludgeoning damage, and either be shoved 5 feet in a direction of your choosing or be knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend Psi Points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Telekinetic Force (you can add multiple modifiers). The points must be spent when choosing the target of the power.</p>
            <p><strong>Crushing</strong>(2 psi points): The target is restrained until the end of its next turn if it fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p><strong>Hammering</strong>(1+ psi points): The target takes 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each point spent if it fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p><strong>Hurling</strong> (1-3 psi points): The target is shoved 10 feet in a direction of your choosing for each point spent if it fails its saving throw.</p>            
            <p><strong>Zone</strong>(1-3 psi points): You can target all creatures in a 5-foot radius of a point within range. The radius doubles for each point spent (5 feet, 10 feet, 20 feet).</p>
            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Telekinesis)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Telekinesis psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>jump, launch object, thunderwave</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>fling, levitate, shatter</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>fly, vortex blast</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>orbital stones, resilient sphere</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>telekinesis, wall of force, shockwav</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATAPULT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FLING" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_VORTEX_BLAST" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ORBITAL_STONES" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_SHOCKWAVE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Kinetic Slam" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_KINETIC_SLAM">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you use the Telekinetic Force power, you can unleash it as a blast of kinetic power. You can use your power as a ranged spell attack (applying damage and effects on hit) instead of requiring a Strength saving throw. You can only select the Hammering modifier when you use it in this way.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use the Telekinetic Force power, you can unleash it as a blast of kinetic power. You can use your power as a ranged spell attack (applying damage and effects on hit) instead of requiring a Strength saving throw. You can only select the Hammering modifier when you use it in this way.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Mental Might" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_MENTAL_MIGHT">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 5 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS,[level:psion:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You learn to focus your mental grip. You can use your Intelligence modifier instead of other ability modifiers when you make an Athletics check.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, you may attempt to grapple or shove a creature within 30 feet, using your mind. When grappling a creature in this way, you can’t move them. Maintaining a grapple at a range greater than your natural reach requires concentration, as if concentrating on a spell, and the grapple ends if concentration is lost</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your Intelligence modifier instead of other ability modifiers when you make an Athletics check.
            Additionally, you may attempt to grapple or shove a creature within 30 feet, using your mind. When grappling a creature in this way, you can’t move them. Maintaining a grapple at a range greater than your natural reach requires concentration, as if concentrating on a spell, and the grapple ends if concentration is lost</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Precise Power" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_PRECISE_POWER">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 9 psion, incompatible with Unchecked Power</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS,[level:psion:9],!ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_UNCHECKED_POWER</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The animate objects spell is added to your Telekinesis Alternate Effects list, which you can cast expending 5 psi points. Additionally, as a reaction to a ranged weapon attack you can see being made against a target within 60 feet of you, you can expend 1 psi point to add or subtract 2d4 to or from that attack roll. You can do this after the attack is rolled, but before you know the outcome of the roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>as a reaction to a ranged weapon attack you can see being made against a target within 60 feet of you, you can expend 1 psi point to add or subtract 2d4 to or from that attack roll. You can do this after the attack is rolled, but before you know the outcome of the roll.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Telekinetic Movement" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TELEKINETIC_MOVEMENT">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can expend 1 psi point to gain 10 additional feet of movement and the effect of spider climb, feather fall, or levitate until the start of your next turn (no action required). At the start of your next turn, you can expend 1 psi point to maintain the effect before it would end.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can expend 1 psi point to gain 10 additional feet of movement and the effect of spider climb, feather fall, or levitate until the start of your next turn (no action required). At the start of your next turn, you can expend 1 psi point to maintain the effect before it would end.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Telekinetic Weapon" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TELEKINETIC_WEAPON">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the Telekinetic Weapons psionic power as part of your Telekinetic Discipline (in addition to your other psionic powers), giving you the ability to fling weapons as per the power.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_TELEKINETIC_WEAPONS" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Telekinetic Barrier" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TELEKINETIC_BARRIER">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You focus your telekinetic power, spreading it thin to create a large barrier. As an action you can expend 2 psi points to create a wall of weak telekinetic force 15 feet high and up to 40 feet long, or as a 15 radius around you. This barrier is visible as small objects hover and float within it. If you create it around yourself, it moves with you when you move. Ranged attacks that pass through this barrier are made with disadvantage as their trajectory is deflected. You can maintain this barrier by concentrating, as if concentrating on a spell, for up to 1 minute after creating it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action you can expend 2 psi points to create a wall of weak telekinetic force 15 feet high and up to 40 feet long, or as a 15 radius around you. This barrier is visible as small objects hover and float within it. If you create it around yourself, it moves with you when you move. Ranged attacks that pass through this barrier are made with disadvantage as their trajectory is deflected. You can maintain this barrier by concentrating, as if concentrating on a spell, for up to 1 minute after creating it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unchecked Power" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_UNCHECKED_POWER">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>level 9 psion, incompatible with Precise Power</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS,[level:psion:9],!ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_PRECISE_POWER</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The fissure spell is added to your Telekinesis Alternate Effects list. Additionally, as a reaction to a melee attack being made against you, you can expend 1 psi point to shove the creature away. The creature must make a Strength saving throw, or be knocked 10 feet backwards. If this puts the attack out of reach, the attack automatically misses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a reaction to a melee attack being made against you, you can expend 1 psi point to shove the creature away. The creature must make a Strength saving throw, or be knocked 10 feet backwards. If this puts the attack out of reach, the attack automatically misses.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FISSURE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
<!--
    <element name="Precognition Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Precognition is the ability to see what lies ahead, piercing the veil of the future. Seeing things that most people cannot a Psion with Precognitive abilites can, to a limited extent, know the future; such a future is known by tracing its roots from the present, and grows more mysterious and cloudy as such roots grow distant.</p>
            <p class="indent">Such a future can be changed by the actions of the present, particularly by knowledge of said future and action to prevent or change it. This is the function most often leveraged by Precognitive Psions, peering into the future to steer around courses they seek to prevent or steer toward a possible outcome they seek.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_PRESCIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_SEEING" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_PRESCIENCE" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_SEEING" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prescience" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_PRESCIENCE">
        <description>
            <p>Your eyes wander to events before they happen. You can add your proficiency to Perception and initiative rolls; if you already are able to add your proficiency to Perception, you can add twice your proficiency</p>
            <p class="indent">If you concentrate on keeping an eye on the future (as if concentrating on a spell), you can use your Intelligence modifier for Wisdom (Perception) checks (instead of Wisdom) and initiative rolls (instead of Dexterity), and you make Intelligence saving throws in place of Dexterity saving throws. You can initiate this concentration at any time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you concentrate on keeping an eye on the future (as if concentrating on a spell), you can use your Intelligence modifier for Wisdom (Perception) checks (instead of Wisdom) and initiative rolls (instead of Dexterity), and you make Intelligence saving throws in place of Dexterity saving throws. You can initiate this concentration at any time.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERCEPTION" />
            <stat name="initiative" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Seeing" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_SEEING">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You concentrate and peer into the stream of future possibilities, gaining insight into what will happen next; you can select one of the following:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can grant advantage to yourself or to a creature that can see or hear you on their next attack roll made before the start of your next turn; if an attack that gained advantage from this feature hits, it deals an extra 1d6 damage.</li>
                <li>You can grant disadvantage on the next attack roll against yourself or a creature that can see or hear you before the start of your next turn; if that attack hits despite the disadvantage, the damaged creature rolls 1d6 and subtracts that from the damage dealt.</li>
                <li>You can spend psi points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Seeing (you can add multiple modifiers).</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Omniscient (1 psi point):</strong> The beneficiary of your Seeing is under the effect of bless and guidance until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Piercing (1+ psi points):</strong> You see through the target’s defenses when granting advantage, increasing the damage of the attack benefiting from advantage by 1d8 per psi point spent if it hits.</p>
            <p><strong>Positioning (1+ psi points):</strong> The beneficiary of your Seeing can immediately move 5 feet per psi point spent (up to their speed) without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
            <p><strong>Thwarting (2 psi points):</strong> The beneficiary of your Seeing has advantage on the next saving throw they make before the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Withheld (0 psi points):</strong> Rather than granting advantage or disadvantage on the next attack, you can grant advantage or disavantage as a reaction to an attack being made until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
     <element name="Alternate Effects (Enhancement)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PRECOGNITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Precognition psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>detect good and evil, future insight</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>augury†, glimpse the future</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>clairvoyance</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>death ward†, divination</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>scrying</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">†augury has the same effect, but doesn’t consult a specific entity when cast in this way</p>
            <p class="indent">†death ward has the same effect, but gives a forewarning to a creature allowing them to avoid death when cast in this way</p>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points.
            †augury has the same effect, but doesn’t consult a specific entity when cast in this way.
            †death ward has the same effect, but gives a forewarning to a creature allowing them to avoid death when cast in this way.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_SPELL_FUTURE_INSIGHT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_GLIMPSE_THE_FUTURE" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    -->

    <element name="Telepathy Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Telepathy is the ability to interact with the minds of other creatures using your psionic abilities.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_TELEPATHIC_COMMUNICATION" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEPATHIC_INTRUSION" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_TELEPATHIC_COMMUNICATION" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEPATHIC_INTRUSION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Telepathic Communication" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_TELEPATHIC_COMMUNICATION">
        <description>
            <p>When you gain this feature, you can communicate telepathically with any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don’t need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language. Creatures you communicate with can reply in kind.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can communicate telepathically with any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don’t need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language. Creatures you communicate with can reply in kind.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Telepathic Intrusion" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEPATHIC_INTRUSION">
        <description>
            <p>You assault the mind of a creature you can see directly. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw, or take 1d8 psychic damage. If the target fails the saving throw, it has disadvantage on attacks made against you until the start of your next turn. You can choose to deal no damage to the creature when it fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend Psi Points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Telepathic Intrusion (you can add multiple modifiers). The points must be spent when choosing the target of the power.</p>
            <p><strong>Meddling (2 psi points):</strong> You make one creature invisible to the target creature or cause the creature to see something that is not there with the effect of minor illusion until the start of your next turn if it fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p><strong>Overwhelmping (3 psi points):</strong> The target is stunned until the end of its next turn if it fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p><strong>Rending (1+ psi points):</strong> The target takes 1d8 psychic damage for each additional point spent on a failed save.</p>
            <p><strong>Terrifying (1 psi point):</strong> The target is frightened of you until the end of your next turn if it fails its saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Telepathy)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Telepathy psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>compelled query, command, frighten</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>detect thoughts, suggestion</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>delve mind, fear</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>dominate beast, compulsion, confusion</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>dominate person, modify memory, telepathic bond</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_COMPELLED_QUERY" spellcasting="Psion" /> 
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" spellcasting="Psion" /> 
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_SPELL_FRIGHTEN" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Psion" /> 
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Psion" /> 
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_DELVE_MIND" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>    
    <element name="Attuned Argument" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_ATTUNED_ARGUMENT">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your telepathic insight allows to adapt and tailor your influence on others. When you make a Charisma check, after you roll but before you know the outcome, you can choose to roll an additional d20 and take the higher result. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all uses on a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When you make a Charisma check, after you roll but before you know the outcome, you can choose to roll an additional d20 and take the higher result.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Empathy" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_EMPATHY">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can psionically link yourself to other creatures. As a reaction to a creature you can see within 120 feet of you taking damage, you can grant them resistance to the damage taken, but you take psychic damage equal to the damage they take (after resistance). The damage you take can’t be reduced or prevented in any way.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the damage would inflict any further negative status effect on the target, you can choose for that effect to affect you instead.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you have any form of telepathic bond that allows long distance telepathic communication affecting the creature taking this damage, the range is unlimited and you do not need to be able to see them.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a reaction to a creature you can see within 120 feet of you taking damage, you can grant them resistance to the damage taken, but you take psychic damage equal to the damage they take (after resistance). The damage you take can’t be reduced or prevented in any way.
            If the damage would inflict any further negative status effect on the target, you can choose for that effect to affect you instead.
            If you have any form of telepathic bond that allows long distance telepathic communication affecting the creature taking this damage, the range is unlimited and you do not need to be able to see them.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mental Image" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_MENTAL_IMAGE">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to use your Telepathy to project images into the minds of creatures with perfect clarity, interposing it over their reality. The spells silent image, major image, hallucinatory terrain and seeming are added to your Telepathic Discipline Alternate Effects list costing psi points equal to their spell level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The spells silent image, major image, hallucinatory terrain and seeming are added to your Telepathic Discipline Alternate Effects list costing psi points equal to their spell level.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mental Influence" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_MENTAL_INFLUENCE">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You specialize in the subtle touch, picking stray thoughts and soothing concerns without overtly intruding upon a mind. You gain expertise in the Persuasion skill, though you are reduced to normal proficiency against creatures that are immune to mental influence or charm (such a creature under the effect of mind blank).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain expertise in the Persuasion skill, though you are reduced to normal proficiency against creatures that are immune to mental influence or charm (such a creature under the effect of mind blank).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Reflected Agony" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_REFLECTED_AGONY">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When a creature within 120 feet that you can see deals damage to you, you can use your reaction to spend 1 or more psi points (up to your psi limit) to share the pain you experienced back at them, dealing 1d10 psychic damage per point spent. The damage this deals can’t exceed the damage taken from the attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature within 120 feet that you can see deals damage to you, you can use your reaction to spend 1 or more psi points (up to your psi limit) to share the pain you experienced back at them, dealing 1d10 psychic damage per point spent. The damage this deals can’t exceed the damage taken from the attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tactical Opening" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TACTICAL_OPENING">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>'
        <prerequisite>level 5 psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY,[level:psion:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can communicate the openings in a creature’s defenses to your allies. When a creature fails a saving throw against your Telepathic Intrusion, you can take the Help action targeting that creature as a bonus action, helping another creature that you can telepathically communicate with. When you take the Help action in this way, the range of it becomes 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature fails a saving throw against your Telepathic Intrusion, you can take the Help action targeting that creature as a bonus action, helping another creature that you can telepathically communicate with. When you take the Help action in this way, the range of it becomes 30 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Telepathic Link" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_TELEPATHIC_LINK">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your Telepathic Communication gains an unlimited range as long as you have communicated with the creature within the last day, and the target willingly maintains the link. However, it takes an action to focus to communicate over distance if you can’t see the target (or for the target to communicate with you if they can’t see you). You can maintain a link with a number of people equal to your Intelligence modifier in this way. You can convey as much in a turn as you could by speaking normally.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Telepathic Communication gains an unlimited range as long as you have communicated with the creature within the last day, and the target willingly maintains the link. However, it takes an action to focus to communicate over distance if you can’t see the target (or for the target to communicate with you if they can’t see you). You can maintain a link with {{intelligence:modifier}} people in this way. You can convey as much in a turn as you could by speaking normally.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
 <element name="Transposition Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Transposition is the ability to modify the properties of space and manipulate dimensional boundaries with your psionic powers.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_FLICKER_STEP" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_PHASE_RIFT" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_FLICKER_STEP" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_PHASE_RIFT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Flicker Step" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_FLICKER_STEP">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Phase Rift" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_PHASE_RIFT">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend Psi Points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Enhancing Surge (you can add multiple modifiers). The points must be spent when choosing the target of the power.</p>
            <p><strong>Fortifying</strong>(1+ psi point): The target gains an additional +1d6 temporary hit points for each point spent.</p>
            <p><strong>Resilient</strong>(3 psi points): the target gains resistance to all damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Savage</strong> (1+ psi point): The target's next weapon attack deals an +1d6 additional damage for each point spent.</p>            
            <p><strong>Swift</strong>(2 psi points): The target gains an additional action. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</p>
            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Transposition)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Transposition psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>heroism, longstrider, unlocked potential</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>alter self, enlarge/reduce, lesser restoration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>haste, protection from energy</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>freedom of movement, stoneskin</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>greater restoration, invested competency</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_UNLOCKED_POTENTIAL" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCCC_PSIONIC_INVESTED_COMPETENCY" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Name1" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_NAME1">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>
<!--
    <element name="Name1" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PT_NAME1">
        <supports>psionic-talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE__</requirements>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


    <element name="Somedisc Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE_SOMEDISC">
        <supports>psionic-discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_SOMEDISC_" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_SOMEDISC_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_TEID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_SOMEDISC_LEPATHIC_COMMUNICATION" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_SOMEDISC_ALTERNATE_EFFECTS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability1" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE__ABILITY1">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability2" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSIONIC_POWER_ABILITY2">
        <supports>Psionic</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend Psi Points up to your per use limit to add the following modifiers to Enhancing Surge (you can add multiple modifiers). The points must be spent when choosing the target of the power.</p>
            <p><strong>Fortifying</strong>(1+ psi point): The target gains an additional +1d6 temporary hit points for each point spent.</p>
            <p><strong>Resilient</strong>(3 psi points): the target gains resistance to all damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p><strong>Savage</strong> (1+ psi point): The target's next weapon attack deals an +1d6 additional damage for each point spent.</p>            
            <p><strong>Swift</strong>(2 psi points): The target gains an additional action. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</p>
            
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic Power</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alternate Effects (Somedisc)" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Craft and Creation" id="ID_KTH_CCC_PSION_DISCIPLINE__ALTERNATE_EFFECTS">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally, when you learn the Somedisc psionic discipline you can use your Psionics feature to cast the following spells as per the rules defined in the feature:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Point Cost</td><td>Alternate Effects</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>heroism, longstrider, unlocked potential</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>alter self, enlarge/reduce, lesser restoration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>haste, protection from energy</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>freedom of movement, stoneskin</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>greater restoration, invested competency</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If a spell can be cast at a higher level, you can spend additional psi points to cast it at a level equal to the psi points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast additional spells using Psi Points</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_PSIONIC_UNLOCKED_POTENTIAL" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Psion" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_CCCC_PSIONIC_INVESTED_COMPETENCY" spellcasting="Psion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    -->
