<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Circle of the City Druid</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-city.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/druid-city.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Circle of the City" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CITY">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The circle of the city is about adaption. The adaption of nature to cities, and the adaption of cities to nature. Druids of the circle see the teeming life of the city as just another ecosystem, one adapted to a special type of life, feeling kinship with the creatures that thrive in such an environment, particularly that which remains wild in the heart of the city, such as rats, pigeons, and cats.</p>
            <p class="indent">While more primeval druids may view them as scarcely different to other city-dwellers, they are no less in tune with nature that other druids, simply tuning into a different, more subtle and pervasive, frequency.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_LIVING_EYES_OF_THE_CITY" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CONTROLLED_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CIVILIZED_BEASTS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_URBAN_ADAPTATION" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_KEEN_SKILLS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_TINY_TRIBUTES" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_LIVING_EYES_OF_THE_CITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CONTROLLED_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CIVILIZED_BEASTS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_URBAN_ADAPTATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_KEEN_SKILLS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_TINY_TRIBUTES" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Circle of the City Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <p>Your adaptation to the urban environment gives you access to certain avenues of magic that are most helpful for overseeing the interests of nature in such an environment. At 2nd, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the spells listed for that level in the Circle of the City Spells table. Once you gain access to one of these spells, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you gain access to a spell that doesn’t appear on the druid spell list, the spell is nonetheless a druid spell for you.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Circle Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td>animal friendship, find familiar</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>detect thoughts, lesser restoration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>clairvoyance, glyph of warding</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>fabricate, stone shape</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>mislead, wall of stone</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" level="2" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="2" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="3" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="3" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="5" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="5" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="7" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="7" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="9" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD"  />
            <grant type="Spell" level="9" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE"  />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Living Eyes of the City" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_LIVING_EYES_OF_THE_CITY">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, when you cast animal friendship, you can target up to a dozen animals of the same type when targeting tiny creatures (such as cats, rats, pigeons, or similar). When a tiny animal is charmed in this way, they can understand you in a limited capacity (such as where something you can describe in terms they would understand is), you can understand them in a limited capacity (such as which direction something is), and will lend you aid in simple tasks as long as it does not place them in danger. They can be convinced to take on greater risks with an appropriate Animal Handling check with the DC determined by the DM.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, any familiar you summon with find familiar gains the ability to communicate with creatures of a type resembling the form it takes, and has advantage on all Animal Handling checks while interacting with beasts it can communicate with. You can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to shift your familiar from one form it can take to another without having to resummon it as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast animal friendship, you can target up to a dozen animals of the same type when targeting tiny creatures (such as cats, rats, pigeons, or similar). When a tiny animal is charmed in this way, they can understand you in a limited capacity (such as where something you can describe in terms they would understand is), you can understand them in a limited capacity (such as which direction something is), and will lend you aid in simple tasks as long as it does not place them in danger. They can be convinced to take on greater risks with an appropriate Animal Handling check with the DC determined by the DM.
            Additionally, any familiar you summon with find familiar gains the ability to communicate with creatures of a type resembling the form it takes, and has advantage on all Animal Handling checks while interacting with beasts it can communicate with. You can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to shift your familiar from one form it can take to another without having to resummon it as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Controlled Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CONTROLLED_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 2nd level, from operating within the confines of a city, you have managed to tame your magic to more freely operate within the limitations of tight urban environments. When you cast a spell that targets an area of effect, you can exclude a 10-foot cube from the area of effect (the cube does not have to be entirely within the area of effect).</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can reduce the area of effect of any spell down to any value between its area of effect and a 5-foot radius, and can cast spells that would otherwise not be able to manifest in the environment (such as casting call lightning in a room less than 60 feet tall), with your spells adapting to fit within your environment.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell that targets an area of effect, you can exclude a 10-foot cube from the area of effect (the cube does not have to be entirely within the area of effect).
            Alternatively, you can reduce the area of effect of any spell down to any value between its area of effect and a 5-foot radius, and can cast spells that would otherwise not be able to manifest in the environment (such as casting call lightning in a room less than 60 feet tall), with your spells adapting to fit within your environment.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Civilized Beasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_CIVILIZED_BEASTS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, when you use your Wild Shape feature to take on the form of a beast, you retain your ability to speak (as long as the beast would normally be able to vocalize sounds at sufficient volume to do so), and become more dexterous and adaptable with paws, claws, or talons, allowing you to use them perform more complicated tasks that might otherwise require hands. You additionally retain the ability to cast spells while using Wild Shape to turn into a beast.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>hen you use your Wild Shape feature to take on the form of a beast, you retain your ability to speak (as long as the beast would normally be able to vocalize sounds at sufficient volume to do so), and become more dexterous and adaptable with paws, claws, or talons, allowing you to use them perform more complicated tasks that might otherwise require hands. You additionally retain the ability to cast spells while using Wild Shape to turn into a beast.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Urban Adaptation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_URBAN_ADAPTATION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 10th level, you become immune to poison and disease, and gain one skill of your choice from Insight, Perception, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, or Stealth. If you have all the listed skills, you can select any skill of your choice instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are immune to poison and disease.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill, Urban Adaptation" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
            <!-- Could add the skill choice here if they had all of those skills-->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Keen Skills" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_KEEN_SKILLS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, you gain proficiency in an additional skill from the list in Urban Adaption.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if a beast you assume the form of is proficient in a skill you are normally proficient in, you gain expertise in that skill while transformed into that beast.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If a beast you assume the form of is proficient in a skill you are normally proficient in, you gain expertise in that skill while transformed into that beast.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill, Keen Skills" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
            <!-- Could add the skill choice here if they had all of those skills-->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tiny Tributes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUID_CITY_TINY_TRIBUTES">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 14th level, your popularity among the tiny animals of the city reaches an all time high. When you complete long rest within the limits of a city, crows, rats, and other tiny creatures bring you minor treasures. You can roll on the following table, or your DM can determine an appropriate item:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Treasure</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>1 probably edible ration.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>1d4 copper pieces.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>1d4 silver pieces.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>1d4 gold pieces.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>1 random piece of adventuring gear.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>1 platinum piece</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">This feature can also provide situationally useful items, such as keys, letters, or situationally useful items.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you complete long rest within the limits of a city, crows, rats, and other tiny creatures bring you minor treasures. You can roll on the following table, or your DM can determine an appropriate item:
            1 - 1 probably edible ration.
            2 - 1d4 copper pieces.
            3 - 1d4 silver pieces.
            4 - 1d4 gold pieces.
            5 - 1 random piece of adventuring gear.
            6 - 1 platinum piece
            This feature can also provide situationally useful items, such as keys, letters, or situationally useful items.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>