<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Feats</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/feats.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <!-- Awakened Undead Feats-->
    
    <element name="Modified Remains" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_MODIFIED_REMAINS">
        <prerequisite>Awakened Undead</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_COLAL_RACE_AWAKENED_UNDEAD</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You've found your remains to be somewhat... customizable. After all, what's the harm in swapping out a few parts here and there? You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Skeleton Carving.</strong> You gain a natural weapon that deals 2d4 damage (piercing or slashing, your choice) or Increase your AC by 1. If you already have a natural weapon and select a natural weapon , you can increase the damage of your existing natural weapon by a d2 step instead (from a d6 to a d8, for example). If a natural weapon has multiple damage dice, increase only one this way.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Modified Remains" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Modified Remains" supports="modified-remains" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Modified Remains (Natural Weapon)" type="Racial Trait" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_MODIFIED_REMAINS">
        <supports>modified-remains</supports>
        <description>
            <p> You gain a natural weapon that deals 2d4 damage (piercing or slashing, your choice).</p>
            <p class="indent">If you already have a natural weapon and select a natural weapon , you can increase the damage of your existing natural weapon by a d2 step instead (from a d6 to a d8, for example). If a natural weapon has multiple damage dice, increase only one this way.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a natural weapon that deals 2d4 damage (piercing or slashing, your choice).
            If you already have a natural weapon and select a natural weapon , you can increase the damage of your existing natural weapon by a d2 step instead (from a d6 to a d8, for example). If a natural weapon has multiple damage dice, increase only one this way.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Modified Remains (AC)" type="Racial Trait" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_MODIFIED_REMAINS">
        <supports>modified-remains</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Increase your AC by 1.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Twice Awakened" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_TWICE_AWAKENED">
        <prerequisite>Awakened Undead</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_COLAL_RACE_AWAKENED_UNDEAD</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You've mastered a second power of Awakening, gaining control of a greater set of powers over your condition. This can be from infusing yourself with energy of that source, or simply learning to imitate the powers natural to that source (for example, a returned spirit may find themselves mastering the powers of a Wandering Spirit after getting used to the condition). You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Secondary Force.</strong> Select an additional option from the Animating Force table, gaining its features.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Twice Awakened" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA"/>            
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Twice Awakened" supports="animating-force-type" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Refined Control" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_REFINED_CONTROL">
        <prerequisite>Awakened Undead</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KTH_COLAL_RACE_AWAKENED_UNDEAD</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain more granular control over your body, even when it is not all attached, allowing it to take advantage of its unnatural properties. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li><strong>Removable Parts.</strong> You can remove a limb and continue to control it. It gains the statistics of a Crawling Claw, but has a blindsight of 5 × your proficiency bonus instead of 30 feet. This crawling claw gains all the abilities of a familiar as per the find familiar spell. You lose use of the limb for anything else while it is not attached. If it is destroyed, you can attach a new limb over the course of a long rest.</li>
                <li><strong>Dullahan.</strong> Being beheaded (for example, by a vorpal sword) is no longer fatal to you, though your body cannot move more than 120 feet from your head.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Removable Parts. You can remove a limb and continue to control it. It gains the statistics of a Crawling Claw, but has a blindsight of {{5xprof}} instead of 30 feet. This crawling claw gains all the abilities of a familiar as per the find familiar spell. You lose use of the limb for anything else while it is not attached. If it is destroyed, you can attach a new limb over the course of a long rest.
            Dullahan. Being beheaded (for example, by a vorpal sword) is no longer fatal to you, though your body cannot move more than 120 feet from your head.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Refined Control" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA"/>  
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <!--Active martial Feats 13-->
    
    <element name="Athlete" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_ATHLETE">
        <prerequisite>4th level and proficiency in Athletics</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4],ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can accomplish mythical feats of athletic prowess. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Athletic Movement.</strong> Gain your choice of a climbing speed or swimming speed equal to your movement speed.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Athletic Feat</strong> special ability (below).</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Athletic Feat</strong><em> Active Ability (Special)</em></p>
            <p>You can perform an outrageous athletic feat. You can do any of the following during your turn:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Jump a distance equal to your movement speed.</li>
                <li>Lift twice your normal lifting capacity until the end of your turn.</li>
                <li>Move at normal speed while carrying or dragging another creature until the end of your turn.</li>
                <li>Make a free Strength or Dexterity saving throw or ability check against an ongoing effect or spell effecting you that would normally take an action or only occur at the end of your turn.</li>
                <li>Take the Dash action as a bonus action.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest. You can use the feature again before completing a rest by taking a level of exhaustion.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Atheletic Feat" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can do any of the following during your turn:
            Jump a distance equal to your movement speed.
            Lift twice your normal lifting capacity until the end of your turn.
            Move at normal speed while carrying or dragging another creature until the end of your turn.
            Make a free Strength or Dexterity saving throw or ability check against an ongoing effect or spell effecting you that would normally take an action or only occur at the end of your turn.
            Take the Dash action as a bonus action.
            You can use the feature again before completing a rest by taking a level of exhaustion.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <select type="Feat Feature" supports="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_SWIM|ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_CLIMB" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Climbing" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_CLIMB">
        <description>
            <p>You gain climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Swimming" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_SWIM">
        <description>
            <p>You gain swimming speed equal to your movement speed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>            
            <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bodyguard" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_BODYGUARD">
        <prerequisite>4th level and fighting style that uses your reaction to defend an allied creature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4],(ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_PROTECTION)</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your reflexes and techniques safeguard your allies. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Leaping Saves.</strong> You can move up to 5 feet before using your reaction to protect an ally with a Fighting Style or Feat. Alternatively, when you use a reaction on a Fighting Style to defend an allied creature while you are already adjacent to them, you can swap positions with that ally after the attack completes as long as your movement speed isn’t zero. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Heroic Intervention</strong> special reaction.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Heroic Intervention</strong><em> Active Ability (Reaction)</em></p>
            <p>As a reaction, when an allied creature within range of your movement speed would take damage, you can move to them and into their space. If the damage came from an attack, you become the target of the attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">They move to an unoccupied space of their choice within 5 feet, or the closest unoccupied space if there are no unoccupied spaces within 5 feet (potentially moving them out of an area of effect, but moving yourself into it).</p>
            <p class="indent">You and the target creature have resistance to all damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can move up to 5 feet before using your reaction to protect an ally with a Fighting Style or Feat. Alternatively, when you use a reaction on a Fighting Style to defend an allied creature while you are already adjacent to them, you can swap positions with that ally after the attack completes as long as your movement speed isn’t zero. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Bodyguard" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_HEROIC_INTERVENTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Heroic Intervention" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_HEROIC_INTERVENTION">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>As a reaction, when an allied creature within range of your movement speed would take damage, you can move to them and into their space. If the damage came from an attack, you become the target of the attack.
            They move to an unoccupied space of their choice within 5 feet, or the closest unoccupied space if there are no unoccupied spaces within 5 feet (potentially moving them out of an area of effect, but moving yourself into it).
            You and the target creature have resistance to all damage until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Breaker" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_BREAKER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You master the breaking of any creature within your grasp. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Punishing Blows.</strong> You have advantage on attack rolls against a creature you are grappling.</li>
                <li>Gain the<strong> Merciless Break</strong> special attack (below)</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Merciless Break</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to inflict a debilitating injury on a creature you are grappling.</p>
            <p class="indent">The creature takes 2d6 + your Strength modifier bludgeoning damage and suffers an injury for 1 minute. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus). While suffering from this injury, the creature subtracts 1d6 from attack rolls and ability checks, and must pass a DC 10 Constitution saving throw to successfully cast a spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">The target creature makes a Constitution saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect of the injury on a success. A creature can spend their action treating their injury to automatically pass the saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on attack rolls against a creature you are grappling.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Bodyguard" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MERCILESS_BREAK" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Merciless Break" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MERCILESS_BREAK">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to inflict a debilitating injury on a creature you are grappling.
            The creature takes {{proficiency}}d6 + {{strength:modifier}} bludgeoning damage and suffers an injury for 1 minute. While suffering from this injury, the creature subtracts 1d6 from attack rolls and ability checks, and must pass a DC 10 Constitution saving throw to successfully cast a spell.
            The target creature makes a Constitution saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect of the injury on a success. A creature can spend their action treating their injury to automatically pass the saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Brute" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_BRUTE">
        <prerequisite>4th level and proficiency in Intimidation</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4],ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your attacks leave your enemies devastated and cowering in fear. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li><strong>Brutal Effort. When you roll damage for a melee weapon attack, you can reroll the weapon’s damage dice and use either total.</strong></li>
                <li>Gain the<strong> Brutal Threat</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Brutal Threat</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to issue a dire threat backed by your killing intent at a creature that can see or hear you within 60 feet. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">On failure, they become frightened for 1 minute. If it fails by 5 or more, it becomes frozen in terror, suffering the paralyzed condition while it is frightened. A frightened creature can repeat its saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on success (if it fails by less than 5 it can end the paralyze effect, but cannot become paralyzed after the initial save).</p>
            <p class="indent">If you kill a target while it is frightened in this way, you can repeat this action as a reaction targeting another creature within 30 feet that can see or hear you bypassing the usual usage restriction of the feature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll damage for a melee weapon attack, you can reroll the weapon’s damage dice and use either total.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_BRUTAL_THREAT" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Brute" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Brutal Threat" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_BRUTAL_THREAT">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to issue a dire threat backed by your killing intent at a creature that can see or hear you within 60 feet. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw.
            On failure, they become frightened for 1 minute. If it fails by 5 or more, it becomes frozen in terror, suffering the paralyzed condition while it is frightened. A frightened creature can repeat its saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on success (if it fails by less than 5 it can end the paralyze effect, but cannot become paralyzed after the initial save).
            If you kill a target while it is frightened in this way, you can repeat this action as a reaction targeting another creature within 30 feet that can see or hear you bypassing the usual usage restriction of the feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Charger" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_CHARGER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You master the reckless rush of smashing into the enemy line. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Heavy Momentum.</strong> If you move at least 20 feet in a direction before making your first melee weapon attack roll on your turn, the attack deals an additional 1d8 damage.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Wild Charge</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Wild Charge</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with making a charge. You or a mount you are controlling can move up to 30 feet in a straight line, flinging your enemies out of your path.</p>
            <p class="indent">This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity. Large or smaller creatures in your path must make a Strength saving throw, or be knocked out of your way and prone. If a creature has no where they can move, they are knocked prone but not moved, and you pass over them. A creature takes 2d6 + your Strength modifier bludgeoning damage on a failed save. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus). Your charge ends early if a creature passes their save. Creatures with a CR equal to less than half of your character level automatically fail their save.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you move at least 20 feet in a direction before making your first melee weapon attack roll on your turn, the attack deals an additional 1d8 damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WILD_CHARGE" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Charger" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wild Charge" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WILD_CHARGE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with making a charge. You or a mount you are controlling can move up to 30 feet in a straight line, flinging your enemies out of your path.
            This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity. Large or smaller creatures in your path must make a Strength saving throw, or be knocked out of your way and prone. If a creature has no where they can move, they are knocked prone but not moved, and you pass over them. A creature takes {{proficiency}}d6 + {{strength:modifier}} bludgeoning damage on a failed save. Your charge ends early if a creature passes their save. Creatures with a CR equal to less than {{level:half}} automatically fail their save.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Destroyer" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_DESTROYER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You bring ruin to the battlefield, cleaving through hordes. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Cleaving Blows. </strong>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, you can apply any overflow damage (damage dealt by the attack over what was required to bring the target to zero) to another creature within 5 feet of the target, if the attack roll would also hit that target.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Whirlwind Slash</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Whirlwind Slas</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with spinning your weapon in a massive arc with great force. All creatures of your choice within 5 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 2d6 + your Strength modifier damage, or half as much on a successful save. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, you can apply any overflow damage (damage dealt by the attack over what was required to bring the target to zero) to another creature within 5 feet of the target, if the attack roll would also hit that target.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WHIRLWIND_SLASH" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Destroyer" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Whirlwind Slash" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WHIRLWIND_SLASH">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with spinning your weapon in a massive arc with great force. All creatures of your choice within 5 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take {{proficiency}}d6 + {{strength:modifier}} damage, or half as much on a successful save.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Durable" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_DURABLE">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You possess an implausible resilience and are capable of amazing feats of endurance. You gain the following the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Rapid Recovery.</strong> When you roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, the minimum number of hit points you regain from the roll equals twice your Constitution modifier (minimum of 2).</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Unyielding Endurance</strong> special reaction</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Unyielding Endurance</strong><em> Active Ability (Reaction)</em></p>
            <p>As a reaction to taking damage, you can brace yourself to weather the blow and any additional blows. Until the start of your next turn, you can reduce all damage taken (including from the damage that triggered this reaction) by your Proficiency bonus and gain advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws. Additionally for the duration, if an attack would reduce you to 0, you can make a Constitution saving throw with a DC to the amount of damage taken. On a success, you are reduced to 1 instead. If you are not incapacitated at the start of your next turn after using this feature, you can expend a number of hit dice up to your proficiency bonus, rolling them to regain hit points as normal.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, the minimum number of hit points you regain from the roll is {{doublecon}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="doublecon" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="doublecon" value="constitution:modifier" />
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_UNYIELDING_ENDURANCE" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Durable" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Unyielding Endurance" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_UNYIELDING_ENDURANCE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>As a reaction to taking damage, until the start of your next turn, you can reduce all damage taken (including from the damage that triggered this reaction) by {{proficiency}} and gain advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws. Additionally for the duration, if an attack would reduce you to 0, you can make a Constitution saving throw with a DC to the amount of damage taken. On a success, you are reduced to 1 instead. If you are not incapacitated at the start of your next turn after using this feature, you can expend up to {{proficiency}} hit dice, rolling them to regain hit points as normal</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Grappler" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_GRAPPLER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You master grappling and leverage to pin and fling your foes. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Quick Grabs. </strong>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike or attempt to grapple as a bonus action.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Martial Toss</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Martial Toss</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to attempt to hurl a creature of your size or smaller. The target must make a Strength saving throw. An object or creature you are grappling automatically fails. If you successfully lift them, you can throw them 20 feet. The range is increased by 10 feet for each size smaller than you the target is.</p>
            <p class="indent">The creature’s movement ends early if it collides with another creature or obstacle. The thrown creature and anything it collides with takes 2d6 + your Strength modifier, and the thrown creature falls prone. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature can choose to fail their save against this ability. You can throw a willing creature more carefully, dealing no damage to them unless they collide with something during their flight.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature to successfully throw a creature or object, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike or attempt to grapple as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MARTIAL_TOSS" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Grappler" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Martial Toss" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MARTIAL_TOSS">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to attempt to hurl a creature of your size or smaller. The target must make a Strength saving throw. An object or creature you are grappling automatically fails. If you successfully lift them, you can throw them 20 feet. The range is increased by 10 feet for each size smaller than you the target is.
            The creature’s movement ends early if it collides with another creature or obstacle. The thrown creature and anything it collides with takes {{proficiency}}d6 + {{strength:modifier}}, and the thrown creature falls prone.
            A creature can choose to fail their save against this ability. You can throw a willing creature more carefully, dealing no damage to them unless they collide with something during their flight.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Line Breaker" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_LINE BREAKER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You smash through your enemies, clearing the way for your allies</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Heavy Impacts. </strong>When you push a creature, if the creature's movement is stopped early by another creature, object, or terrain, they take 1d4 bludgeoning damage for each 5 feet moved before the collision.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Might Impact</strong> special attack </li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Mighty Impact</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to slam an enemy backwards. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On failure, it takes 2d6 + your Strength modifier damage and is pushed 15 feet away from you. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is pushed 5 feet away from you. The distance the target is pushed is reduced by 5 feet for every size larger than you it is. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you push a creature, if the creature's movement is stopped early by another creature, object, or terrain, they take 1d4 bludgeoning damage for each 5 feet moved before the collision.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MIGHTY_IMPACT" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Line Breaker" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mighty Impact" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_MIGHTY_IMPACT">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to slam an enemy backwards. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On failure, it takes {{proficiency}}d6 +{{strength:modifier}} damage and is pushed 15 feet away from you. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is pushed 5 feet away from you. The distance the target is pushed is reduced by 5 feet for every size larger than you it is.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ruffian" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_RUFFIAN">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You have turned kicking people when they're down into an art form. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Painful Critical.</strong> When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack against a creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded or dazed† until the start of your next turn. This does not affect undead, constructs, or other creatures that can feel no pain.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Dirty Strike</strong> special ability</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Dirty Strike</strong><em> Active Ability (Special)</em></p>
            <p>When you make a melee weapon attack, you can follow up with a dirty trick (a knee to the gut, handful of sand to eyes, etc.). The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On failure, they become your choice of blinded or dazed† (your choice) for 1 minute. The target can repeat its saving throw at the end of each of their turns. A creature can spend their action treating their condition to automatically pass the saving throw. Once you use this against a target once, they are ready for subsequent attempts and automatically pass saving throws against it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature to successfully blind or daze a creature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack against a creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded or dazed† until the start of your next turn. This does not affect undead, constructs, or other creatures that can feel no pain.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_DIRTY_STRIKE" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ruffian" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Dirty Strike" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_DIRTY_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 Sucess/Short Rest">
            <description>When you make a melee weapon attack, you can follow up with a dirty trick (a knee to the gut, handful of sand to eyes, etc.). The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On failure, they become your choice of blinded or dazed† (your choice) for 1 minute. The target can repeat its saving throw at the end of each of their turns. A creature can spend their action treating their condition to automatically pass the saving throw. Once you use this against a target once, they are ready for subsequent attempts and automatically pass saving throws against it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Storm Shooter" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_STORM_SHOOTER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Raining Death. </strong>If you kill a creature within a single ranged weapon attack (reducing it from maximum hit points to 0 hit points) using the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as a bonus action that turn.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Arrow Storm </strong>special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Arrow Storm</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks by firing innumerable pieces of ammunition into the sky which rain down around a point within 60 feet of you. All creatures within 10 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 2d6 + your Dexterity modifier damage, or half as much on success. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus). A number of pieces of ammunition are consumed equal to the number of targets that make the save against the ability times two.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you kill a creature within a single ranged weapon attack (reducing it from maximum hit points to 0 hit points) using the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as a bonus action that turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_ARROW_STORM" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Storm Shooter" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Arrow Storm" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_ARROW_STORM">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks by firing innumerable pieces of ammunition into the sky which rain down around a point within 60 feet of you. All creatures within 10 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take {{proficiency}}d6 + {{dexterity:modifier}} damage, or half as much on success. A number of pieces of ammunition are consumed equal to the number of targets that make the save against the ability times two.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Striker" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_STRIKER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You move like the wind, striking faster than your foes can see. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Battlefield Dancer.</strong> Each time you hit a creature, your movement speed increases by 5 feet until the end of your turn. If you attack and hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can pass through its space, treating it as difficult terrain.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Slashing Dash</strong> special attack.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Slashing Dash</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a rapid burst of movement, moving up to 30 feet along any surface in a straight line.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can move on vertical or horizontal surfaces with this movement, can pass through creatures, and do not provoke attacks of opportunity, but cannot pass through objects or terrain. If you are carrying a weapon you are proficient with when you take this action, each time you pass through a creature, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice) damage of your weapon type on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Each time you hit a creature, your movement speed increases by 5 feet until the end of your turn. If you attack and hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can pass through its space, treating it as difficult terrain.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_SLASHING_DASH" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Striker" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Slashing Dash" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_SLASHING_DASH">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a rapid burst of movement, moving up to 30 feet along any surface in a straight line.
            You can move on vertical or horizontal surfaces with this movement, can pass through creatures, and do not provoke attacks of opportunity, but cannot pass through objects or terrain. If you are carrying a weapon you are proficient with when you take this action, each time you pass through a creature, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes {{proficiency}}d6 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice) damage of your weapon type on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Weapon Thrower" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_WEAPON_THROWER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You excel at hurling objects, with a remarkably lack of concern for aerodynamics.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase. </strong>Increase your Strength or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Reckless Aerodynamics.</strong> All melee weapons gain the thrown 20/60 property for you, unless they already had the thrown property with a greater range.</li>
                <li>Gain the <strong>Thunderbolt Throw</strong> special attack.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Thunderbolt Throw</strong><em> Active Ability (Attack)</em></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to hurl a Small or smaller object (including weapons for creatures of Medium size) at a target. Make an attack treating the object as a simple melee weapon with the thrown 60/180 property unless it already has a longer thrown range. On hit, the creature takes 2d6 + your Strength modifier bludgeoning damage (replaced by the weapons damage type when throwing a weapon) and must make a Constitution saving throw or be knocked prone and dazed†. The number of d6 increases by one when your proficiency bonus increases (with the total number of d6 equaling your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_THUNDERBOLT_THROW" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Weapon Thrower" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Thunderbolt Throw" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_THUNDERBOLT_THROW">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to hurl a Small or smaller object (including weapons for creatures of Medium size) at a target. Make an attack treating the object as a simple melee weapon with the thrown 60/180 property unless it already has a longer thrown range. On hit, the creature takes {{proficiency}}d6 + {{strength:modifier}} bludgeoning damage (replaced by the weapons damage type when throwing a weapon) and must make a Constitution saving throw or be knocked prone and dazed.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Weapon Feats 15-->
    <element name="Axe Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_AXE_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You wield an axe like a force of nature, maximizing and embodying its relentless and unstoppable power. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Axe Rush. </strong>While wielding a handaxe, battleaxe, or greataxe, you can use a bonus action to move up to 5 feet and add 1d6 to your next attack and damage roll with an axe.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Axe Rush: While wielding a handaxe, battleaxe, or greataxe, you can use a bonus action to move up to 5 feet and add 1d6 to your next attack and damage roll with an axe.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Axe Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bow Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_BOW_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>Your relentless practice with a bow grants you the following benefits while using one:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ranging Shots.</strong> When you miss a ranged weapon attack with a bow, your next ranged weapon attack roll with a bow has advantage.</li>
                <li><strong>Overwatch.</strong> As a bonus action, you can ready a shot until the start of your next turn. If a creature moves 5 feet or more while within 30 feet of you while you have a shot readied, you can use your reaction to make a ranged weapon attack against that creature with a −5 penalty to the attack roll.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Ranging Shots. When you miss a ranged weapon attack with a bow, your next ranged weapon attack roll with a bow has advantage.
            Overwatch. As a bonus action, you can ready a shot until the start of your next turn. If a creature moves 5 feet or more while within 30 feet of you while you have a shot readied, you can use your reaction to make a ranged weapon attack against that creature with a −5 penalty to the attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dagger Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_DAGGER_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You wield daggers with perfection and poise, able to use them fluidly in any situation.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Dagger Tricks.</strong> You can draw or stow any number of daggers during your turn. You have advantage on any ability check to conceal your daggers.</li>
                <li><strong>Improved Critical.</strong> Your attacks with daggers score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Swift Stabbing.</strong> When you use two-weapon fighting using a dagger in both hands, you can take both attacks as part of the Attack action on your turn (without expending your bonus action). You can only make this attack once per turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Dagger Tricks. You can draw or stow any number of daggers during your turn. You have advantage on any ability check to conceal your daggers.
            Improved Critical. Your attacks with daggers score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.
            Swift Stabbing. When you use two-weapon fighting using a dagger in both hands, you can take both attacks as part of the Attack action on your turn (without expending your bonus action). You can only make this attack once per turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Flail Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FLAIL_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>Your mastery with a flail allows you to use the challenging weapon with deadly skill. You gain the following benefits while wielding a flail:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Dangerous Swings.</strong> When you miss a melee weapon attack made with a flail, you can make a new attack roll against another creature you of your choice within the weapon’s range. You cannot attack the same creature twice this way.</li>
                <li><strong></strong>Wind Up. As a bonus action, you can whirl the flail building momentum. The next attack you make with it before the end of your turns an additional 1d8 damage on hit.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Dangerous Swings. When you miss a melee weapon attack made with a flail, you can make a new attack roll against another creature you of your choice within the weapon’s range. You cannot attack the same creature twice this way.
            Wind Up. As a bonus action, you can whirl the flail building momentum. The next attack you make with it before the end of your turns an additional 1d8 damage on hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Harpoon Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_HARPOON_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You are resourceful and skilled when it comes the use of harpoons, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase. </strong>Increase your Strength or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Throwing Arm.</strong> The normal range of your thrown weapons is doubled.</li>
                <li><strong>Harpoon.</strong> As an action, you can use 30 feet of rope to turn any javelin, spear, or trident into a harpoon. When you throw that harpoon at a target 30 feet or less from you, you can pull it back to your hand as a bonus action. If the attack hit the target and the target is no more than one size larger than you, when you pull the harpoon back to you, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw against a DC of 8 + your Strength modifier + your proficiency bonus. On failure, you drag the target up to 20 feet toward you.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Throwing Arm. The normal range of your thrown weapons is doubled.
             Harpoon. As an action, you can use 30 feet of rope to turn any javelin, spear, or trident into a harpoon. When you throw that harpoon at a target 30 feet or less from you, you can pull it back to your hand as a bonus action. If the attack hit the target and the target is no more than one size larger than you, when you pull the harpoon back to you, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw against a DC of 8 + {{harpoon:dc}}. On failure, you drag the target up to 20 feet toward you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="harpoon:dc" value="8" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="harpoon:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="harpoon:dc" value="strength:modifier" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Harpoon Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Impact Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_IMPACT_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered heavy blows with bludgeoning weapons. When you hit a creature with a maul or greatclub, you gain a charge of momentum until the end of your current turn. You can expend your momentum charges as a bonus action on one of the following abilities.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Knock Back</strong> (Requires 1 or more charges of momentum): You push a creature within reach of you 5 feet per charge of momentum directly away from you. The distance they are pushed decreases by 5 feet for every size larger than you they are (for example, if you are Medium pushing a Large creature, you need to push them 10 feet to move them 5 feet).</li>
                <li><strong>Take Down</strong> (Requires 2 charges of momentum): You force a creature within reach of you to make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</li>
                <li><strong>Bonk!</strong> (Requires 1 or more charges of momentum): You expend the momentum slamming into a creature within 5 feet of you, dealing 1d4 bludgeoning damage per charge of momentum.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit a creature with a maul or greatclub, you gain a charge of momentum until the end of your current turn. You can expend your momentum charges as a bonus action on one of the following abilities.
            >Knock Back (Requires 1 or more charges of momentum): You push a creature within reach of you 5 feet per charge of momentum directly away from you. The distance they are pushed decreases by 5 feet for every size larger than you they are (for example, if you are Medium pushing a Large creature, you need to push them 10 feet to move them 5 feet).
            Take Down (Requires 2 charges of momentum): You force a creature within reach of you to make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.
            Bonk! (Requires 1 or more charges of momentum): You expend the momentum slamming into a creature within 5 feet of you, dealing 1d4 bludgeoning damage per charge of momentum.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lance Master" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_LANCE_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You use maximize the effectiveness of a lance, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Impaled Movement.</strong> While you are mounted, if you strike a creature smaller than your mount with a lance, you can push that creature until the end of your turn, you make another attack, or you move in something other than a straight line. This movement counts as if you are grappling the creature for the duration of the movement, and your mounts movement speed is reduced to half while pushing them.</li>
                <li><strong>Piercing Charge.</strong> When you hit an attack with a lance after traveling at least 10 feet, you can make an additional attack at another creature behind the target hit with disadvantage, as long as they are in reach of your weapon (you can move between attacks, but only in a straight line) with disadvantage. You can continue to repeat this until you miss, run out of movement, or run out of creatures in a line to hit.</li>
                <li><strong>Expert Handling.</strong> A lance no longer requires two-hands when you aren’t mounted.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Impaled Movement. While you are mounted, if you strike a creature smaller than your mount with a lance, you can push that creature until the end of your turn, you make another attack, or you move in something other than a straight line. This movement counts as if you are grappling the creature for the duration of the movement, and your mounts movement speed is reduced to half while pushing them.
            Piercing Charge. When you hit an attack with a lance after traveling at least 10 feet, you can make an additional attack at another creature behind the target hit with disadvantage, as long as they are in reach of your weapon (you can move between attacks, but only in a straight line) with disadvantage. You can continue to repeat this until you miss, run out of movement, or run out of creatures in a line to hit.
            Expert Handling. A lance no longer requires two-hands when you aren’t mounted.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Morning Star Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_MORNING_STAR_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered the use of a morning star, and are able to leverage greater effectiveness from it. You gain the following features:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Improved Critical.</strong> Your attacks with morning stars score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Rend.</strong> Your critical strikes wound the target. The target loses 1d10 hit points at the end of each of their turns until the wound is healed. The target or any creature within 5 feet of it can make a DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check as an action to heal the wound.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Improved Critical. Your attacks with morning stars score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.
            Rend. Your critical strikes wound the target. The target loses 1d10 hit points at the end of each of their turns until the wound is healed. The target or any creature within 5 feet of it can make a DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check as an action to heal the wound.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Morning Star Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Natural Weapon Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_NATURAL_WEAPON_EXPERT">
        <prerequisite>Have one or more natural weapons</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You master the use of your natural weapons, granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ferocity.</strong> As a bonus action, you can make a single weapon attack with your natural weapon.</li>
                <li><strong>Natural Perfection.</strong> Your natural weapon damage die increases to 1d6. If it is already 1d6 or greater, it increases by d2 (or one step higher), up to a maximum of 1d12.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Ferocity. As a bonus action, you can make a single weapon attack with your natural weapon.
            Natural Perfection. Your natural weapon damage die increases to 1d6. If it is already 1d6 or greater, it increases by d2 (or one step higher), up to a maximum of 1d12.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pike Master" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_PIKE_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You master the effective use of a pike, making the most of its extreme range.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Extended Reach.</strong> Your reach with a pike increases by 5 feet on your turn.</li>
                <li><strong>Set for Charge.</strong> If you haven’t yet moved this turn, you can use your bonus action to set for charge, reducing your movement speed to 0 and gaining a second reaction that can only be used to make attacks of opportunity until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li><strong>Zone Control.</strong> While wielding a pike, creatures provoke an attack of opportunity when they enter the reach of the pike.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Extended Reach. Your reach with a pike increases by 5 feet on your turn.
            Set for Charge. If you haven’t yet moved this turn, you can use your bonus action to set for charge, reducing your movement speed to 0 and gaining a second reaction that can only be used to make attacks of opportunity until the start of your next turn.
            Zone Control. While wielding a pike, creatures provoke an attack of opportunity when they enter the reach of the pike.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Stinger" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_STINGER">
        <description>
            <p>You specialize in the quiet and agonizing kill with subtle weapons. You gain the following benefits related to blowguns and darts:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Dexterity, Wisdom, or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Efficient Poisons.</strong> When you apply a poison blowgun needle or dart, you can apply it to twice as many pieces of ammunition.</li>
                <li><strong>Hidden Death.</strong> If you attack while hidden from a target with a blowgun or dart, you can make a Dexterity (Stealth) check with a −5 penalty for each time you’ve hit the target this turn against their passive Wisdom (Perception) score (no action required). On a success, you remain hidden from that target, though the target will know which general direction you are in.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Efficient Poisons. When you apply a poison blowgun needle or dart, you can apply it to twice as many pieces of ammunition.
            Hidden Death. If you attack while hidden from a target with a blowgun or dart, you can make a Dexterity (Stealth) check with a −5 penalty for each time you’ve hit the target this turn against their passive Wisdom (Perception) score (no action required). On a success, you remain hidden from that target, though the target will know which general direction you are in.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Stinger" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Swordmaster" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_SWORDMASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Your swordplay leverages every advantage to build momentum, allowing you to strike or defend in new ways. When wielding a sword, you gain a special Swordplay d6 die each time you successfully attack a creature with it. You can have a maximum number of Swordplay dice equal to your proficiency bonus. You lose all accumulated dice if you stop wielding a sword or end your turn without making an attack with a sword.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend your Swordplay dice on the following abilities:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Sword Parry</strong>. As a reaction to being hit by a melee weapon attack, you can expend your Swordplay dice, rolling them and reducing the damage taken by the amount rolled. If the amount rolled exceeds the damage taken, the attacker takes damage equal to the difference.</li>
                <li><strong>Sword Finisher.</strong> As a bonus action when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend your Swordplay dice, rolling them and dealing additional damage equal to the roll.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When wielding a sword, you gain a special Swordplay d6 die each time you successfully attack a creature with it. You can have a max of {{proficiency}} and are lost if you stop wielding a sword or end your turn without making an attack.
            Sword Parry. As a reaction to being hit by a melee weapon attack, you can expend your Swordplay dice, rolling them and reducing the damage taken by the amount rolled. If the amount rolled exceeds the damage taken, the attacker takes damage equal to the difference.
            Sword Finisher. As a bonus action when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend your Swordplay dice, rolling them and dealing additional damage equal to the roll.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Warhammer Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_WARHAMMER_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>Your mastery over a warhammer ensures that your blows never fail to wear down the enemy, becoming an inexorable threat to any foe. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Battering Blows.</strong> When you miss a melee weapon attack with the warhammer, the target takes half the weapon damage the attack would have dealt. This does not count as a hit for things that require you to hit the target (such as spells, Divine Smite, or similar features), but does include modifiers to the attack damage roll.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Battering Blows. When you miss a melee weapon attack with the warhammer, the target takes half the weapon damage the attack would have dealt. This does not count as a hit for things that require you to hit the target (such as spells, Divine Smite, or similar features), but does include modifiers to the attack damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Warhammer Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="War Pick Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_WAR_PICK_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered the use of a war pick, and are able to tear down the most formidable foes.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Increase your Strength or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Siege Pick.</strong> Attacks you make with the war pick against objects deal double damage.</li>
                <li><strong>Sunder.</strong> When you hit a target that is wearing armor or benefiting from natural armor, you can use your bonus action to sunder the target, temporarily leaving them vulnerable. The next attack roll against that creature has advantage</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Siege Pick. Attacks you make with the war pick against objects deal double damage.
            Sunder. When you hit a target that is wearing armor or benefiting from natural armor, you can use your bonus action to sunder the target, temporarily leaving them vulnerable. The next attack roll against that creature has advantage</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="War Pick Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Whip Expert" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_WHIP_EXPERT">
        <description>
            <p>You master using a whip, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity or Constitution ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Expert Handling.</strong> Whips gain the Light property for you and you can use a whip to extend your reach for certain object interactions, such as opening and closing doors, picking up objects, or similar simple interactions.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Whip Tricks</strong> special attacks.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Whip Tricks</strong></p>
            <p>You master the manipulation of a whip to allow a level of extreme control over its use.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you make a weapon attack with a whip, you can replace the attack with a trick, forcing the enemy to make a Dexterity saving throw saving with a DC of 8 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice) + your proficiency bonus. If the target fails its saving throw, you can perform any of the following tricks against it:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Sudden Yank.</strong> You wrap the whip around a Medium or smaller target, and yank them 5 feet towards you</li>
                <li><strong>Tangle Weapon.</strong> You tangle one weapon the target is wielding, giving them disadvantage on attacks with that weapon until the start of your next turn, or until they miss an attack. You cannot make attacks with the whip used to make the attack until they free the weapon.</li>
                <li><strong>Whip Trip.</strong> You tangle a Large or smaller creature’s feet, causing them to fall prone.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Expert Handling. Whips gain the Light property for you and you can use a whip to extend your reach for certain object interactions, such as opening and closing doors, picking up objects, or similar simple interactions.
            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Whip Expert" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <grant type="Feat Features" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WHIP_TRICKS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Whip Tricks" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WHIP_TRICKS">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you make a weapon attack with a whip, you can replace the attack with a trick, forcing the enemy to make a Dexterity saving throw saving with a DC of 8 + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice) + {{proficiency}}. If the target fails its saving throw, you can perform any of the following tricks against it:
            Sudden Yank. You wrap the whip around a Medium or smaller target, and yank them 5 feet towards you
            Tangle Weapon. You tangle one weapon the target is wielding, giving them disadvantage on attacks with that weapon until the start of your next turn, or until they miss an attack. You cannot make attacks with the whip used to make the attack until they free the weapon.
            Whip Trip. You tangle a Large or smaller creature’s feet, causing them to fall prone.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Combat Style Feats 2-->
    <element name="Versatile Weapon Master" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Versatile_Weapon_Master">
        <description>
            <p>You are an expert on the fluid use of versatile weapons, changing stances to fit any situation. When you draw a versatile weapon you are proficient with, or start your turn while wielding one, you can enter a special stance as long as you aren’t wielding other weapons or a shield.</p>
            <p class="indent">This lasts until the start of your next turn, drop or sheath your weapon, or equip a shield. Each stance provides modifiers to your melee weapon attacks made with the versatile weapon while in that stance:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Neutral Stance:</strong> You add +1 to your attack rolls, damage rolls, and armor class.</li>
                <li><strong>Power Stance:</strong> You don’t add your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls, but add twice your Proficiency bonus to your damage rolls.</li>
                <li><strong>Accuracy Stance:</strong> You add twice your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls (instead of just your Proficiency Bonus, but don’t add your ability modifier to damage rolls.</li>
                <li><strong>Defensive Stance:</strong> You don’t add your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls, but if you hit at least one attack against a hostile creature, you can add your proficiency bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you draw a versatile weapon you are proficient with, or start your turn while wielding one, you can enter a special stance as long as you aren’t wielding other weapons or a shield.
            This lasts until the start of your next turn, drop or sheath your weapon, or equip a shield. Each stance provides modifiers to your melee weapon attacks made with the versatile weapon while in that stance:
            Neutral Stance: You add +1 to your attack rolls, damage rolls, and armor class.
            Power Stance: You don’t add your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls, but add twice your Proficiency bonus to your damage rolls.
            Accuracy Stance: You add twice your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls (instead of just your Proficiency Bonus, but don’t add your ability modifier to damage rolls.
            Defensive Stance: You don’t add your Proficiency bonus to attack rolls, but if you hit at least one attack against a hostile creature, you can add your proficiency bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element><element name="Lightning Strikes" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Lightning_Strikes">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered wielding weapons with lightning speed, granting the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Quick Draw.</strong> Whenever you make an attack, you can draw a light melee weapon as part of taking the attack.</li>
                <li><strong>Twin Strike.</strong> When you make an attack while wielding more than one light melee weapon and make an attack with one of them, you can subtract the damage dice of another light melee weapon you are carrying from the attack roll to add twice its damage dice to the damage roll of that attack on hit.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Quick Draw. Whenever you make an attack, you can draw a light melee weapon as part of taking the attack.
            Twin Strike. When you make an attack while wielding more than one light melee weapon and make an attack with one of them, you can subtract the damage dice of another light melee weapon you are carrying from the attack roll to add twice its damage dice to the damage roll of that attack on hit.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <!-- Mystic Path Feats 13-->
    <element name="One With Wind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_One_With_Wind">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered the supernatural ability striking like the wind, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Wisdom ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Wind Walker.</strong> You are not affected by difficult terrain or additional movement costs when the difficult terrain or movement cost comes from strong winds (such as the gust of wind spell).</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Wind Strike</strong> special attack. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Wind Strike</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a special attack that lets you vanish into the wind before striking a number of nearby creatures with a weapon you are carrying in a flurry of blows, before reform from the wind within 5 feet of one of the creatures attacked. You can attack a number of creatures in this way equal to your proficiency bonus, but can only strike each creature once. You can strike creatures within a range of 5 × your proficiency bonus feet (for example when you proficiency bonus is +2, you can strike creatures within 10 feet).</p>
            <p class="indent">Each time you strike a creature, make a melee weapon attack, dealing 1d6 + your Mystic Path modifier damage on a hit. The damage increases by 1d6 each time your proficiency bonus increases.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Wind Walker. You are not affected by difficult terrain or additional movement costs when the difficult terrain or movement cost comes from strong winds.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="One With Wind" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM"/>
            <grant type="Feature Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WIND_STRIKE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Wind Strike" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WIND_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a special attack that lets you vanish into the wind before striking a number of nearby creatures with a weapon you are carrying in a flurry of blows, before reform from the wind within 5 feet of one of the creatures attacked. You can attack {{proficiency}} creatures in this way, but can only strike each creature once. You can strike creatures within a range of {{5xprof}} feet.
            Each time you strike a creature, make a melee weapon attack, dealing {{windstrike}}d6 + your Mystic Path modifier damage on a hit.
            </description>            
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="5xprof" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="windstrike" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="windstrike" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="windstrike" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="windstrike" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="windstrike" value="1" level="17" />
                
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wind Affinity" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_WIND_AFFINITY">
        <description>
            <p>You are touched by the winds, either from a blessing of a powerful entity or through focused mastery and study of their essence, allowing you to borrow and harness their power.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn the windborne weapon and manipulate wind cantrips and the become wind spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it a level equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You learn the become wind spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it at level {{proficiency}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_WINDBORNE_WEAPON" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_MANIPULATE_WIND" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WIND" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wind Slash" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Wind_Slash">
        <description>
            <p>The wind conveys the will of your attacks, granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity or Wisdom ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Cloudbreaker.</strong> You can cut dust, fog, or clouds. As an attack as part of the attack action, you can clear a 30 foot cone of dust, fog, or cloud. Depending on the source of the obscuring effect, the area may become obscured again after 1d4 rounds.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Wind Slash</strong> special attack.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Wind Slash</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a special attack, launching a blades of wind at targets within 60 feet. You launch a number of blades equal to your proficiency modifier, but can increase the number of attacks made by giving up additional attacks you can make as part of the Attack action (launching one additional attack for each attack forgone). The blades are ranged weapon attacks using your Mystic Path modifier. Each blade deals 1d6 + your Mystic Path modifier slashing damage on damage on hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Cloudbreaker. As an attack as part of the attack action, you can clear a 30 foot cone of dust, fog, or cloud. Depending on the source of the obscuring effect, the area may become obscured again after 1d4 rounds.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Wind Slash" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WIND_SLASH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Wind Slash" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WIND_SLASH">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a special attack, launching a blades of wind at targets within 60 feet. You launch {{proficiency}} blades, but can increase the number of attacks made by giving up additional attacks you can make as part of the Attack action (launching one additional attack for each attack forgone). The blades are ranged weapon attacks using your Mystic Path modifier. Each blade deals 1d6 + your Mystic Path modifier slashing damage on damage on hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fire Dancer" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FIRE_DANCER">
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You harbor within your soul an ember of the flame of life akin to the power of a phoenix. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Constitution or Charisma ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Resilient Life.</strong> You gain advantage on death saving throws. If you have Explosive Rejuvenation available when you would fail your 3rd death saving throw, it automatically activates instead.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Explosive Rejuvenation </strong> special bonus action.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Explosive Rejuvenation</strong></p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can unleash the power of the ember within your soul, exploding with fire. You regain 2d4 hit points, and all creatures within 10 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The fire damage and hit points regard increase by 1d4 each time your proficiency increases (remaining equal to your proficiency bonus).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Resilient Life. You gain advantage on death saving throws. If you have Explosive Rejuvenation available when you would fail your 3rd death saving throw, it automatically activates instead.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Fire Dancer" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_EXPLOSIVE_REJUVENATION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Explosive Rejuvenation" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_EXPLOSIVE_REJUVENATION">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can unleash the power of the ember within your soul, exploding with fire. You regain {{proficiency}}d4 hit points, and all creatures within 10 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fire Affinity" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Fire_Affinity">
        <description>
            <p>You are granted a special affinity with fire, allowing you to borrow and harness its power.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn the fire bolt and manipulate fire cantrips, and learn the become fire spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it a level equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You learn the fire bolt and manipulate fire cantrips, and learn the become fire spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it at level {{proficiency}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_MANIPULATE_FIRE" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_FIRE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Lightning Leaper" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Lightning_Leaper">
        <description>
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
            <p>You master the art of moving like lightning... literally. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Intelligence ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Lightning Dodge.</strong> When you succeed a dexterity saving throw, you can teleport up to 5 feet.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Lightning Leap</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Lightning Leap</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack by turning into lightning, leaping (as lightning) to a creature or empty space within 10 feet. If you target a creature, you can target a chain of creatures within 10 feet of the previous target, targeting a number of creatures equal to your proficiency bonus. Each creature you target makes a Dexterity saving, taking 2d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save. You then teleport to an empty spot of your choice adjacent to the last target of the chain. The damage increases by 1d6 and the range (initial and jump distance) increases by 5 feet whenever your proficiency bonus increases.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Lightning Dodge. When you succeed a dexterity saving throw, you can teleport up to 5 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Fire Dancer" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_LIGHTNING_LEAP" />
        </rules>
    </element>   
    <element name="Lightning Leap" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_LIGHTNING_LEAP">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack by turning into lightning, leaping (as lightning) to a creature or empty space within 10 feet. If you target a creature, you can target a chain of creatures within {{lightningleaprange}} feet of the previous target, targeting a number of creatures equal to your proficiency bonus. Each creature you target makes a Dexterity saving, taking {{proficiency}}d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save. You then teleport to an empty spot of your choice adjacent to the last target of the chain..</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="lightningleaprange" value="10" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="lightningleaprange" value="5" level="5" />
            <stat name="lightningleaprange" value="5" level="9" />
            <stat name="lightningleaprange" value="5" level="13" />
            <stat name="lightningleaprange" value="5" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lightning Rod" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Lightning_Rod">
        <description>        
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
            <p>You learn to store lightning energy within your body. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Intelligence ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Lightning Draw.</strong> When a creature within 10 feet of you takes lightning damage, as a reaction you can redirect that damage to yourself.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Lightning Burst</strong> special attack.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Lightning Burst</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack by unleashing lightning that blasts all targets of your choice within 10 feet of you. Each target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 2d6 lightning damage. On success they take half as much damage. The lightning damage increases by 1d6 each time your proficiency bonus increases.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Lightning Draw. When a creature within 10 feet of you takes lightning damage, as a reaction you can redirect that damage to yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_LIGHTING_BURST" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Lightning Rod" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Lightning Burst" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_LIGHTING_BURST">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack by unleashing lightning that blasts all targets of your choice within 10 feet of you. Each target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take {{proficiency}}d6 lightning damage. On success they take half as much damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Shaper" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Earth_Shaper">
        <description>
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
            <p>You have mastered a special connection to the earth and can call upon the stones buried in to heed your calls.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Wisdom modifier by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li><strong>Stone Forming.</strong> You learn the stone forming cantrip</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Stonewall</strong> special action.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Stonewall</strong></p>
            <p>As an action, you cause a 20 foot high, 1 foot thick wall of stone to erupt from the ground either in a 20 foot radius around you, or in a 30-foot long straight line that has a least one part of the wall within 20 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">The wall lasts for up to 10 minutes. The wall can be destroyed, and has an AC of 16 and a number of hit points equal to 5 × your character level (the entire ring sharing the same hit points, crumbling to dust when reduced to zero). The wall immediately crumbles if you fall unconscious.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_STONE_FORMING" />
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Earth Shaper" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_STONEWALL" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Stonewall" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_STONEWALL">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>As an action, you cause a 20 foot high, 1 foot thick wall of stone to erupt from the ground either in a 20 foot radius around you, or in a 30-foot long straight line that has a least one part of the wall within 20 feet of you.
            The wall lasts for up to 10 minutes. The wall can be destroyed, and has an AC of 16 and {{stonewallhp}} HP (the entire ring sharing the same hit points, crumbling to dust when reduced to zero). The wall immediately crumbles if you fall unconscious.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="stonewallhp" value="level" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="stonewallhp" value="level" />
            <stat name="stonewallhp" value="level" />
            <stat name="stonewallhp" value="level" />
            <stat name="stonewallhp" value="level" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Binder" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Earth_Binder">
        <description>
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
            <p>Your mastery of the earthly powers allows you to call upon its power to entrap foes. You gain the following the benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Wisdom modifier by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong></strong>Grasping Earth. Once per turn, when you hit a Large or smaller creature with a melee weapon attack as part of the Attack action, its speed is reduced by 10 feet. If it is flying, it must a Strength saving throw, or fall prone.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Earthen Wave</strong> special attack</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Earth Wave</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with causing the ground beneath a target creature within 30 feet to surge and warp. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw against your Mystic Path DC. On failure, you can cause one of the following effects of your choice:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Earth Spike.</strong> The target takes 2d6 + your Mystic Path modifier piercing damage.</li>
                <li><strong>Earth Grip.</strong> The target is grasped by the earth and their movement speed becomes 0 until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li><strong>Earth Slam.</strong> The target takes 1d6 + your Mystic Path modifier bludgeoning damage and is knocked 5 feet in a direction of your choice.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>On success, they take no damage and suffer no additional effects. The damage the target takes is increased by 1d6 when your proficiency bonus increases.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Grasping Earth. Once per turn, when you hit a Large or smaller creature with a melee weapon attack as part of the Attack action, its speed is reduced by 10 feet. If it is flying, it must a Strength saving throw, or fall prone.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Earth Binder" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_EARTHEN_WAVE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Earthen Wave" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_EARTHEN_WAVE">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with causing the ground beneath a target creature within 30 feet to surge and warp. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw against your Mystic Path DC. On failure, you can cause one of the following effects of your choice:
            Earth Spike. The target takes {{proficiency}}d6 + your Mystic Path modifier piercing damage.
            Earth Grip. The target is grasped by the earth and their movement speed becomes 0 until the start of your next turn.
            Earth Slam. The target takes {{earthwave}}d6 + your Mystic Path modifier bludgeoning damage and is knocked 5 feet in a direction of your choice.
            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="earthwave" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="earthwave" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="earthwave" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="earthwave" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="earthwave" value="1" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Stone Affinity" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Stone_Affinity">
        <description>
            <p>You are granted a special affinity with stone, allowing you to borrow and harness its power.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn the impact and manipulate earth cantrip, and learn the become stone spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it a level equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You learn the impact and manipulate earth cantrip, and learn the become stone spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it at level {{proficiency}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules usage="1/Short Rest">
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IMPACT" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_MANIPULATE_EARTH" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_STONE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Water Affinity" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Water_Affinity">
        <description>
            <p>You are granted a special affinity with water, allowing you to borrow and harness its power. </p>
            <p class="indent">You learn the water bullet and manipulate water cantrip, and learn the become water spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it a level equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You learn the water bullet and manipulate water cantrip, and learn the become water spell. You can cast it innately without expending a spell slot once, regaining the ability to so when you complete a short or long rest. When you cast it this way, you cast it at level {{proficiency}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_WATER_BULLET" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_MANIPULATE_WATER" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WATER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Water Weaver" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_Water_Weaver">
        <description>
        <prerequisite>4th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:4]</requirements>
            <p>You have mastered a special connection to water and can beckon it to your call. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Ability Score Bonus.</strong> Increase your Strength, Dexterity, or Wisdom ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li><strong>Water Walker.</strong> You can walk on top of surfaces made of water as if they are solid ground.</li>
                <li>You gain the <strong>Water Whip</strong> special attack.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong>Water Whip</strong></p>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with creating and using a whip of water. You can slam this into a creature within 30 feet of you, forcing it to make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes a number of d8 damage equal to your proficiency bonus, and is knocked 10 feet in a direction of your choice (including straight up, if you so choose). On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t moved.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Water Walker. You can walk on top of surfaces made of water as if they are solid ground.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Water Weaver" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM"/>
            <grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WATER_WHIP" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Water Whip" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_WATER_WHIP">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with creating and using a whip of water. You can slam this into a creature within 30 feet of you, forcing it to make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes {{proficiency}}d8 damage, and is knocked 10 feet in a direction of your choice (including straight up, if you so choose). On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t moved.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- Esoteric Arts Feats 3-->
    <element name="Featname" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATNAME">
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong></strong></li>
                <li><strong></strong></li>
                <li><strong></strong></li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="name" type="Feat Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_FEATURE_name">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- Transformation Arts Feats 4-->
    <!-- Additional Feats 6-->

    <!-- Blood magic feats-->
    <element name="Hemomancer" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_HEMOMANCER">
        <prerequisite>Spellcasting or Pact Magic Feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can sacrifice your essence to cast spells with the "(blood magic)" tag in place of expending a spell slot. To do so, sacrifice 5 hit points per level of the spell. These hit points sacrificed can count towards the hit point cost of the blood Material component of the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can cast a total number of spell levels in this manner equal to your character level, but casting a spell of 6th level or higher this way drains your vitality in a more profound way, causing you to gain levels of exhaustion equal to the number of levels over 5th the spell is (1 level for a 6th-level spell, 2 for a 7th-level spell, etc.).</p>
            <p class="indent">You cannot cast spells over 5th level this way while you have any levels of exhaustion. The total number of spell levels you can cast in this manner resets when you take a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can sacrifice your essence to cast spells with the "(blood magic)" tag in place of expending a spell slot. To do so, sacrifice 5 hit points per level of the spell. These hit points sacrificed can count towards the hit point cost of the blood Material component of the spell.
            You can cast a total number of spell levels in this manner equal to your character level ({{level}}), but casting a spell of 6th level or higher this way drains your vitality in a more profound way, causing you to gain levels of exhaustion equal to the number of levels over 5th the spell is.
            You cannot cast spells over 5th level this way while you have any levels of exhaustion. The total number of spell levels you can cast in this manner resets when you take a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Vital Blood" type="Feat" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_FEAT_VITAL_BLOOD">
        <prerequisite>Spellcasting or Pact Magic Feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your mastery of blood magic has given it magical properties, brimming with unnatural vitality. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li> Increase your Constitution, Wisdom, Intelligence, or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>Bloody Vitality. When you complete a short rest while you are bloodied (have less than half your maximum hit points) before rolling any hit dice, you regain hit points equal to your spellcasting modifier.</li>
                <li>Crimson Potion. As an action, you can take 1d4 slashing damage to splatter some of your blood on a willing creature within 5 feet, granting them the effects of a Potion of Healing. Once you use this ability you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Bloody Vitality. When you complete a short rest while you are bloodied (have less than half your maximum hit points) before rolling any hit dice, you regain hit points equal to your spellcasting modifier.
            Crimson Potion. As an action, you can take 1d4 slashing damage to splatter some of your blood on a willing creature within 5 feet, granting them the effects of a Potion of Healing. Once you use this ability you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement +1 (Vital Blood)" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>