<elements>
    <info>
        <name>KibblesTasty SPells</name>
        <description></description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Acid Bubble" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACID_BUBBLE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a bubble of acid that floats to the target point before bursting in a shower of acid. Each creature and object within 5 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 3d4 acid damage, or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 2d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 action</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Acid Rain" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACID_RAIN">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Acid rain begins falling within a 40-foot-radius, 60-foot-high cylinder centered on a point you choose within range. When a creature moves into the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 6d4 acid damage and is covered in acid. On a success, a creature takes half the initial damage and is not covered in acid.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature takes 3d4 acid damage if it ends its turn while covered in acid. The target or a creature within 5 feet of it can end this damage by using its action to clear away the acid.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Acidic Pit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACIDIC_PIT">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You open a pit filled with acid at a point within range. Each creature within 10 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it falls 5 feet into a pit of acid below, taking 6d4 + 6 acid damage. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage from the flooding acid and can use its reaction to move up to its movement speed to the closest point outside of the area. If it cannot take a reaction or reach a safe space, it automatically fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature ends its turn in the pit, it takes 2d4 acid damage. The acid in the pit remains potent for 1 minute, after which it turns to vile sludge that deals no further damage. The pit remains filled with sludge until filled or cleared.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aero Barrage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AERO_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create four lances of rapidly spinning condensed wind and hurl them at targets within range. You can direct the lances at one target or different ones.</p>
            <p class="indent">Make a ranged spell attack for each lance. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 slashing damage and is knocked 10 feet backwards.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you create one additional lance for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aether Lance" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AETHER_LANCE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gather raw aether in your hand and expel it in a lance of power, forming a line 30 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in the line takes 8d4 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aether Storm" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AETHER_STORM">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a storm of aether, erupting from a point of your choice within range. The aether storm fills a 10-foot radius, 40-foot-high cylinder. When the storm appears, each creature within its area takes 8d4 force damage. When a creature enters the storm or moves within it, it takes 2d4 force damage for every 5 feet it travels, and whenever a creature ends its turn in the storm it takes an additional 8d4 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your subsequent turns, you can move the storm up to 15 feet in any direction and cause it to fling forth a hail of force bolts that seek out up to 3 targets of your choice within 15 feet of the storm. Each target takes 3d4 + 3 force damage from the bolts.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage dealt when the storm is cast, when a creature ends its turn in the storm, or when a creature is struck by a force bolt increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alacrity" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ALACRITY">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the start of your next turn, your speed is doubled, you gain a +2 bonus to AC, you have advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and you gain an additional action. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are under the effect of haste, you gain no benefit from this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aldricor's Elemental Rebuke" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ALDRICORS_ELEMENTAL_REBUKE">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You manipulate some of the incoming elemental energy, harnessing its power in your hand. The damage you take from the triggering attack or effect is cut in half. You can then hurl the energy back at the creature that damaged you if it is within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 1d8 damage of the triggering type on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">reaction</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Angelic Slash" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANGELIC_SLASH">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon a giant spectral angel that appears around you before crashing its greatsword down in a line. All creatures in a line 30 feet long and 5 feet wide in a direction of your choice must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 5d8 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature takes an additional 1d8 damage if it is undead or a fiend.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Animate Shadow" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANIMATE_SHADOW">
        <supports>Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Targeting a creature you can see within range, you bring its shadow to life under your control. If the creature has a challenge rating above 3 or has no shadow (either due to its nature or from the lack of a light source to cast one) the spell fails. Creatures without a challenge rating are immune to this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Otherwise, a copy of the creature is created using its game statistics in a space adjacent to the creature (on the opposite side as the nearest bright light). The shadow has no legendary actions, legendary resistance, and cannot cast spells. The shadow has hit points equal to half the target’s hit points, and it looks like a mirrored version of the creature it was summoned from, formed from inky black smoke. The shadow is resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical sources while in darkness. The shadow is vulnerable to all damage while in bright light, and always vulnerable to fire, lightning, and radiant damage. If the shadow is killed, the target creature it was summoned from casts no shadows for the next 8 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">The shadow acts immediately after the target's turn, and without further direction it attempts to follow and takes the Attack action against the target. As a reaction to the shadow starting its turn, you can exert control over it and cause it to move and take its action as you direct.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels. </i></strong>When you cast this spell using a 5th- or 6th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating of the target increases to 4. When you cast it using a 7th- or 8th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating increases to 5. When you cast it using a 9th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating increases to CR 6.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">summon</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a smoked stained mirror</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Anvil Drop" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANVIL_DROP">
        <supports>Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure an anvil 500 feet above a point you can see. At initiative count 0 (losing ties) on the next round, the anvil hits the ground. Each creature within 5 feet of the target point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it moves to the closest unoccupied space outside of the radius. If no space is available or a creature cannot move, it automatically fails. On a failure, a creature takes 10d10 + 10 bludgeoning damage. Creatures within 20 feet of the target point take 4d4 thunder damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the path of the anvil (directly above the target point) is interrupted, the creature or object above it is hit first. If the creature or object is killed or destroyed, the anvil continues, though the damage dealt is subtracted from the final impact damage of the anvil.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the anvil deals less than 80 damage, the anvil survives the impact, and is an anvil of moderate quality.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When cast with a 9th-level spell slot, the range of the spell becomes 120 miles, though you must still be able to see the target (such as via scrying).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Ablation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_ABLATION">
        <supports>Inventor, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a piece of worn armor or clothing and imbue it with magic. For the duration, the wearer gains 4 temporary hit points. If these temporary hit points are exhausted, the creature gains 1 fewer temporary hit points at the start of its next turn. When the temporary hit points would reach 0, the spell ends. Temporary hit points gained from this spell are lost when the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> The initial temporary hit points increase by 1 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">temporary hit points</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Conduit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_CONDUIT">
        <supports>Sorcerer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You tap directly into the arcane weave. For the duration, you have resistance to all damage from magical sources besides force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of each of your turns while tapped into this power, you and all creatures with 5 feet of you take 1d6 Force damage. The damage increases by 1d6 each turn to a maximum of 4d6 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Weapon" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_WEAPON">
        <supports>Inventor, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a weapon and imbue it with magic. For the duration, the weapon counts as a magical weapon and all damage dealt by it becomes force damage. When you cast this on a weapon with the ammunition property, the weapon doesn't consume ammunition when fired, and does not need to be reloaded.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using spell slot of 3rd or 4th level, the duration becomes hours. When you use a spell slot of 5th level or higherthe duration becomes 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcanist's Sword" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANISTS_SWORD">
        <supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a glowing sword-shaped plane of force that hovers within range for the duration. When the sword appears and as a bonus action on subsequent turns, you can give the sword one of the following commands.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Attack:</em></strong> The sword moves up to 20 feet toward a creature and makes a melee spell attack against it. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 3d10 + your spellcasting ability modifier</li>
                <li><strong><em>Guard:</em></strong> The sword moves up 20 feet into a creature’s space and grants the creature half cover as it attempts to deflect incoming attacks. The first time a hostile creature comes within 5 feet of the sword, the sword makes a melee spell attack against that creature. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 3d10 + your spellcasting ability modifier. The sword cannot attack again until you command it again</li>
                <li><strong><em>Whirl:</em></strong> The sword moves up to 20 feet toward a point and then begins to spin in a deadly whirl. A creature that starts in the sword’s space or passes within 5 feet of the sword on its turn must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 3d10 force damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a miniature platinum sword with a grip and pommel of copper and zinc, worth 250 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arctic Aura" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCTIC_AURA">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the duration you unleash a freezing aura. Any creature starting its turn within 20 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 2d8 cold damage and its speed is reduced to 0 until the start of its next turn. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage and its speed halved.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action on each of your turns for the duration, you can actively control the aura, excluding a number of creatures in the area up to your spellcasting modifier from the effects until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arctic Breath" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCTIC_BREATH">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A line of freezing arctic wind 30 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 2d8 cold damage and its speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't slowed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, slow</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Avalanche" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AVALANCHE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause the earth to ripple, triggering an avalanche of rock and stone to surge forward in a line 60 feet long and 15 feet wide. The length of the line is doubled if cast on a steeply sloped surface. Each creature caught in the surging tumble of rocks must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 6d10 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone. On a failure by 5 or more, it is stunned until the end of its next turn, and on a failure by 10 or more it is moved to the closest free space at the end of the line created by the spell. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and suffers none of the spell’s other effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell creates a 15 by 15 foot area of difficult terrain at the end of the line created by the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 6th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Awaken Rope" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AWAKEN_ROPE">
        <supports>Bard, Inventor, Occultist, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can touch a rope of 10 to 60 feet in length and issue it a single command, selecting from the following options.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Bind.</em></strong> The rope attempts to bind a creature of your choice within 20 feet of you. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw or become restrained until it is freed. A creature can use its action to make a DC 10 Strength check, freeing itself or another creature within its reach on a success. Dealing 5 slashing damage to the rope (AC 10) also frees the creature without harming it, ending the effect and destroying the rope.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Fasten.</em></strong> The rope flies up 60 feet and ties one end of itself to an object or surface that a rope could be tied to, before becoming inanimate again, hanging from the object.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Grab.</em></strong> The rope lashes out at an object within its length and grabs one Small or smaller object that is not being worn by a creature, pulling it back to your hand. If the object is being carried by a creature, the creature can make a Strength saving throw. On a success, the object is not pulled.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target a chain instead of a rope. It has the same available actions, but it has a DC 15, an AC of 15, and resistance to slashing damage when taking the Bind action.</p>
            <p class="indent">When cast with a spell slot of 3rd level or higher targeting a rope, that rope is magically imbued for 1 minute, gaining an DC of 15, an AC 20, and 20 hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">10 to 60 feet of cord or rope, worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Baba's Walking Hut" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BABAS_WALKING_HUT">
        <supports>Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a hut, cabin, or other building no more than 15 feet by 15 feet by 10 feet. On completion of the spell, the building grows legs large enough to support it, as well as the structural integrity needed stand and move, and becomes a gargantuan creature. It has 250 hit points, an AC of 12, and a walking speed of 20 feet. If it drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">On your turn, you can direct it to move (no action required) and it will continue to move as directed until you direct it to stop or reaches its destination. It can take no actions, but if it walks over a Large or smaller creature, you can direct it to attempt to step on that creature, and that creature must succeed a Dexterity saving throw, or take 2d10 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast this spell on the same building every day for a year, the spell lasts until dispelled, or you cast it on another building.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a chicken leg</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bad Blood" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BAD_BLOOD">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to corrupt the blood of a creature you can see within range. Creatures without blood are immune to this effect. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 1d12 poison damage and becomes poisoned for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target. On a failure, it takes an additional 1d4 poison damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target an additional creature for each slot level above 2nd. All targets must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">poison</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of rotten meat</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Beam of Annihilation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BEAM_OF_ANNIHILATION">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a beam of pure energy, creating a line of power 60 feet long and 10 feet wide, which persists until the start of your next turn. When you cast the spell, choose between cold, fire, force, or lightning damage for the beam. Any creature starting its turn in the beam must make a Dexterity saving throw. It takes 8d8 damage of the beam’s type on a failure or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">While you are concentrating on this spell, your speed is 0. At the start of each of your turns, you can use your action to maintain the beam in place or redirect it, rotating it up to 90 degrees in any direction. Any creature the beam passes through completely in this rotation must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 4d8 damage of the beam's type.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you do not use your action to maintain or redirect the beam, the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, fire, lightning, force</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 3 rounds</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Fire" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_FIRE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental flames. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to fire damage and to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain. The first time you enter another creature’s space on a turn, it takes 1d6 fire damage.</li>
                <li>Any time you are hit by a melee attack, the attacker takes 1d6 fire damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Stone" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_STONE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You solidify into stone. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You are petrified (granting you resistance to all damage).</li>
                <li>Your AC becomes 20.</li>
                <li>You gain 15 temporary hit points. Any remaining temporary hit points fade when the spell ends.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you gain an additional 5 temporary hit points for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Water" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WATER">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental water. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain. The first time you move through a Large or smaller creature on a turn, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Wind" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WIND">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental wind. Until the start of the next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to lightning damage and bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You gain a flying speed of 30 feet, can move through the space of other creatures, and ignore difficult terrain, but will fall if you are in the air when the spell ends.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Befuddling Curse" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BEFUDDLING_CURSE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You befuddle a creature’s mind, causing it to believe two similarly-sized objects or creatures it can see have been swapped. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, it believes the two things have been swapped.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each time the creature interacts with, attacks, or is attacked by a swapped target, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the spell on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!-- original spell listed a material component but did not specify what the material was -->
    <element name="Bile Beam" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BILE_BEAM">
        <supports>Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a beam of acid in a line 5 feet wide and 100 feet long, which stops early if it impacts a creature, Large or larger object, or solid surface. If the beam hits a creature, the creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 12d4 acid damage and an additional 4d4 acid damage at the end of its next turn. On a success, it takes half as much initial acid damage and no additional damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature or object is killed or destroyed by the beam, the beam continues until it impacts another creature or object.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast the spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d4 for each level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (100-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Binding Curse" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BINDING_CURSE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You bind a creature to a point within 5 feet of it, causing glowing chains of light to connect it to that point. For the duration of the spell, if the creature attempts to move away from the point, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be unable to move more than 5 feet away from the point until the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target starts its turn more than 10 feet from the binding point, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be dragged 5 feet toward the binding point.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blackhole" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLACKHOLE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a miniature black hole at a point within range. An event horizon forms in a 15-foot radius around the point, engulfing anything (including light, sound, and magical effects) in the area.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the black hole appears, each creature within 15 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw to avoid being engulfed. On a success, it can move up to its movement speed out of the event horizon of the black hole. If it cannot move to a safe space outside of the event horizon, it automatically fails the save and is engulfed.</p>
            <p class="indent">An engulfed creature is compressed into the point at the center of the spell, taking 12d12 bludgeoning damage at the start of each of its turns while engulfed. Its speed is 0, and it is blinded, deafened, and restrained while engulfed. As an action, an engulfed creature can attempt to forcibly exit the black hole by making a Strength ability check against your spell save DC. On a success, the creature appears in an empty space at the edge of the event horizon.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any spells, effects, terrain, or items that are not being worn or carried that are engulfed within the event horizon vanish and are destroyed. Magical items of Legendary or Artifact rarity are not destroyed, instead reappearing on the ground where the sphere was when the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the spell persists, all movement away from it while within 120 feet of it is considered difficult terrain. All ranged attacks that pass within 120 feet of it have disadvantage. When a creature starts its turn within 120 feet of the black hole, it is pulled 5 feet toward the black hole. At the start of the caster’s turn, all objects within 120 feet of the black hole that weigh less than 1000 pounds, are not being worn or carried, and are not attached to the ground are pulled 20 feet toward the black hole.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade Mirage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLADE_MIRAGE">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Ranger, Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You twist illusions around a melee weapon you are holding. When you cast the spell, and as a bonus action on your subsequent turns for the duration, you can feint with the illusory blades, distracting a creature within 5 feet of you and giving you advantage on the next weapon attack against it before the end of the turn. The spell ends early if you let go of the weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, a creature that can see you can make an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. On a success, it becomes immune to the spell's effects.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade Vortex" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLADE_VORTEX">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You fill the air in a 10-foot radius around you with spinning blades until the start of your next turn. When the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it takes 4d4 slashing damage. Until the spell ends, you have half cover against all ranged attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level higher, the damage increases by 1d4 for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spinning top</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blastwave" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLASTWAVE">
        <supports>Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a fiery blast of power outward in all directions. Each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 4d8 thunder damage and 4d8 fire damage and is knocked back 10 feet. On a success, it takes half as much and is not knocked back.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blazing Beacon" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLAZING_BEACON">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Warlock, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are bathed in holy light, shedding bright light up to 30 feet and dim light for additional 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any creature that targets you with an attack roll or spell that requires them to see you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, they are blinded until the start of their next turn. A creature with darkvision makes this roll with disadvantage. A creature without eyes automatically passes their saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blizzard" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLIZZARD">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a howling blizzard of swirling clouds of ice and snow which fills a 30-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered at a point you can see within range. The area becomes heavily obscured and difficult terrain. Any creature that starts its turn within the area or enters it for the first time on its turn must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 6d8 cold damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 6th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boil Blood" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BOIL_BLOOD">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point at a creature that has taken slashing or piercing damage within the last minute and make its blood heat to boiling. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or its blood overheats. At the start of each of its turns, it takes 3d4 fire damage and is crippled with agony, turning all terrain into difficult terrain for it.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 2d4 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bond Item" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BOND_ITEM">
        <supports>Inventor</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch an item weighing no more than 100 pounds and form a link with it. Until the spell ends, you can recall it to your hand as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">If another creature is holding or wearing the item when you try to recall it, it can attempt a Charisma saving throw to retain possession of the item. On a success, the spell ends. The creature makes this save with advantage if it has possessed the item for more than 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Barrier" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BARRIER">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a line of low brambles that erupts from a space on the ground you can see within range. This line is 30 feet long and 5 feet wide, made up of six 5-foot squares of brambles. Each patch must connect to another patch and be placed on the ground. The bramble patches are difficult terrain and any creature entering a square of brambles takes 4d4 piercing damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, its speed becomes 0 until the end of its turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The brambles wither and die after 1 day if the area isn’t suitable for them to grow. A creature can clear a 5-foot square with 1 minute of labor, or instantly by inflicting at least 5 points of fire damage. The brambles crumble to dust immediately if you cast this spell again.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can create two additional 5-foot squares of brambles for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Binding" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BINDING">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Brambles burst from your hand, lashing out at a target within range. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 4d4 piercing damage and, if it is Large or smaller, becomes entangled by brambles. While entangled by brambles, it can’t move, but it can free itself as an action (taking no additional damage) or rip itself free using half of its movement and taking an additional 2d4 piercing damage. On a success, it takes half as much damage and isn't entangled by brambles.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, both the initial damage and the damage taken ripping free of the brambles increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Brilliant Blade" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRILLIANT_BLADE">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You brandish the weapon used in this spell’s casting, holding it aloft as it flashes with brilliant light. Each creature within 20 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature is blinded until the end of your next turn. On a success, it is blinded until the end of your current turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">blind</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burial Barrage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURIAL_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unearth five heavy chunks of earth or stone and hurl them at targets within range. You can hurl them at one target or several. Make a ranged spell attack for each hurled object. On a hit, a target takes 1d12 + 1 bludgeoning damage, and if it is Large or smaller, falls prone. Attacks made as part of this spell have advantage against prone targets, and ignore disadvantage for making a ranged attack against a prone target farther than 5 feet away.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can hurl one additional object for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burn" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURN">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Melee</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You ignite a brilliant flame around your hand that sears anything you touch. Make a melee spell attack against a creature or object within range. On a hit, the target takes 1d12 fire damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d12 when you reach 5th level (2d12), 11th level (3d12), and 17th level (4d12).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burning Strike" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURNING_STRIKE">
        <supports>Paladin, Ranger, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a weapon or a piece of ammunition, imbuing it with licking flames. The next time you attack with the empowered item, it bursts into brilliant fire. On a hit, the target takes an additional 4d4 fire damage and begins to burn. On a miss, the target takes half as much damage and does not start to burn. A burning target sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet, and takes 1d4 fire damage at the end of each of its turns. The target or another creature within 5 feet can use an action to extinguish the flames.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you target a weapon with the light property, you can immediately make a single weapon attack with it as part of the same action as casting the spell. Once you make one attack with the targeted item, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, both the initial and ongoing burn damage are increased by 1d4 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ammunition or a weapon worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Carnivorous Garden" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CARNIVOROUS_GARDEN">
        <supports>Druid</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon clinging plant growth in four 15-foot squares you can see within range, and a snarling carnivorous plant in the central space of each area. Each 15-foot square is difficult terrain. When you cast the spell, each plant makes one attack against a creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The plants make melee spell attacks with your spell attack modifier, dealing 2d8 piercing damage on hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of one or more of the carnivorous plants, the plants automatically attack that creature unless you use your reaction to prevent them from doing so.</p>
            <p class="indent">The plants have AC 14 and 30 hit points, and have vulnerability to fire and slashing damage. Each plant regains all its hit points at the start of your turn if it has at least 1 hit point, and dies if it is reduced to zero hit points. When the spell ends, the difficult terrain disappears, except where the plants themselves were. This difficult terrain also disappears if the plant was killed with fire damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can summon 1 additional carnivorous plant for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">summon</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a dried carnivorous plant</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Chromatic Breath" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CHROMATIC_BREATH">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a willing creature that has a mouth and can breathe, imbuing it with the power to expel elemental energy. When you cast the spell, select one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. Until the spell ends, the target can use its action to exhale a powerful elemental gust in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 3d6 damage of the selected type. On a success, it takes half as much damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a fragment of a dragon’s scale</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Chrono Conjunction" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CHRONO_CONJUNCTION">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a reaction to a creature rolling a save, ability check, or attack roll, you search all possible timelines and merge the outcome you desire with reality. Select a value from 1 to 20 as the outcome of the roll. An unwilling creature can attempt to resist by making a Charisma saving throw; on a success, the spell has no effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you cast this spell, you cannot cast it again until 24 hours have passed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature you can see within 60 feet rolls a save, ability check, or attack roll.</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the past or future</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Clay Touch" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CLAY_TOUCH">
        <supports>Druid, Inventor, Occultist, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You reach to a creature within range and attempt to turn its armor to soft clay. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, the target’s armor (including natural or magical defenses) becomes soft and malleable, though retaining its form, and provides no protection against attacks, reducing the target’s AC to 10 + its Dexterity modifier for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can touch a nonmagical object that isn’t being worn or carried and is no larger than 2 feet in any dimension, reducing its AC and the DCs of any Strength checks to damage it to 5 for the duration of the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">compona small clump of clayent</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cold Snap" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_COLD_SNAP">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>With a snap of your fingers, a swirling burst of freezing wind erupts at a point you choose within range. Each creature in a 5-foot-radius sphere centered must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 3d8 cold damage and becomes coated in ice, reducing its speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is not slowed.</p>
            <p class="indent">The ground in the area is covered with slick ice and snow, making it difficult terrain until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 ft (5-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Commandment" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_COMMANDMENT">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You issue a divine order to another creature you can see within range that can hear and understand you, invoking divine authority to compel them. If the target intentionally violates the issued order, it takes 4d6 radiant damage. Once a creature takes damage this way, they cannot take damage again from it until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some examples of orders you can issue would include ordering the target not to attack, not to move, or not to breathe. If you issue an impossible order, the spell ends immediately.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crackle" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRACKLE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create three arcs of lightning striking targets in range. You can direct them at one target or several. Make a ranged spell attack for each arc. On a hit, a target takes 1d12 lightning damage. If three or more arcs hit a single target, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become shocked, stunning it until the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create one additional arc for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crashing Wave" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRASHING_WAVE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A wave of water sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked 10 feet away from you. If a creature is knocked into a wall, another creature, or fails by 5 or more, it is additionally knocked prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and is not knocked back. If there is a source of water of at least 5 cubic feet within 5 feet of you when you cast the spell, you can displace that water, increasing the range of the spell to a 30 foot cone.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell lot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (15-foot cone)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Create Pit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CREATE_PIT">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You choose a 10-foot square area on the ground in an area of dirt or natural stone you can see. The ground buckles and opens into a 10-foot deep pit. If the surface is not large enough to contain the pit, the spell fails. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, a creature jumps to a space 5 feet outside the spell's radius. On a failure, a creature falls to the bottom of the pit (taking normal falling damage). The sides of the pit are rough, and can be climbed. A creature that saves but cannot locate an empty space to move to falls prone, hanging from the edge of the pit, and cannot stand until it moves out of the pit area or drops into it. The pit remains until filled.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the pit is 5 feet deeper for each slot level above 1st, to a maximum of 20 feet deep.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell may fail if the pit would breach another opening (such as a room or cavern below), as that would be failing to contain the pit. The GM has wide discretion on what surfaces are valid targets for this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet (10-foot square)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crescent Wind Slash" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRESCENT_WIND_SLASH">
        <supports>Bard, Ranger, Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You make a series of three slashes, each one magically releasing a razor-sharp blast of wind at a target within range. You can launch them at one target or several.</p>
            <p class="indent">Make a weapon attack with the weapon used in the casting of this spell for each slash. On hit, the target takes slashing damage equal to 1d6 + the ability modifier used for the attack.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can create one additional slash for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crippling Agony" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRIPPLING_AGONY">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can inflict crippling agony on one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become crippled with horrific pain. Whenever the target moves more than half of its speed or takes any action, it takes 1d6 necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The target can repeat the saving throw, ending the spell on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a joint bone</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cruel Puppetry" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRUEL_PUPPETRY">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to bind a creature's soul to a doll, forging a sympathetic link between the two. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the creature becomes bound to the doll. On a success, the creature is not bound and the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a target first fails its save and as an action on subsequent turns for the duration, you can perform one of the following actions:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Restrain.</em></strong> Hold the doll still, causing the creature to be restrained until start of your next turn.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Move.</em></strong> Force the doll to move, causing the creature to move 15 feet in a direction of your choice it is able to move.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Attack.</em></strong> Force the doll to swing its arm, causing the creature to make a melee weapon attack against a creature of your choice within its reach.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Stab!</em></strong> Stab the doll, dealing 4d6 piercing damage to the target.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Rip!</em></strong> Rip the doll in half, dealing 4d12 necrotic damage to the target, destroying the doll, and ending the spell.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Each time you use your action to manipulate the doll, the target can repeat its saving throw afterward at disadvantage. On a success, the spell ends. Once a creature has been targeted by this spell, it cannot be targeted again for 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast with a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the range of the spell becomes unlimited, as long as the target is on the same plane as the caster.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing, necrotic, restrained</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small humanoid doll worth at least 5 gp and something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—both of which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crushing Singularity" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CRUSHING_SINGULARITY">
        <supports> Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an overwhelming gravitational singularity at a point within range, lasting until the start of your next turn. When you cast this spell, each creature within 15 feet of the point must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, a creature is pulled to the closest available space adjacent to the singularity and takes 6d6 bludgeoning damage. On a success, it takes half damage and is not pulled.</p>
            <p class="indent">While within 15 feet of the singularity, any attempt to move away costs twice as much movement. If a creature ends its turn within 15 feet of the singularity, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, it takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage and is dragged back to the closest available spot adjacent to the singularity.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell lot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Curse of Impotence" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_CURSE_OF_IMPOTENCE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You curse a target creature, causing an overwhelming sense of powerlessness to wash over it. Any time it attempts any action which would deal damage, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a success, it takes action as normal. On a failure, it completes the action, but the action deals no damage to any targets.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dancing Object" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DANCING_OBJECT">
        <supports>Bard, Inventor, Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You bring a Tiny nonmagical object that is not being worn or carried to life. The object uses the following stats:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Dancing Object</em></strong></li>
                <li><em>Tiny Construct</em></li>
                <li>AC: 18</li>
                <li>HP: 20</li>
                <li>Speed 30 ft., fly 30 ft. (hover)</li>
                <li>STR 4, DEX 18, CON 10, INT 3, WIS 3, CHA 1</li>
                <li><strong>ACTIONS- Slam -</strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> your spellcasting attack modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d4 + your spellcasting modifier damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">If the object is a weapon, it deals the weapon’s damage dice + your Spellcasting modifier of the weapon’s damage type instead. The spell can only animate one-handed weapons without the special property this way.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can mentally command the animated object as long as it is within 60 feet of you. You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the object is securely attached to a surface or a larger object, such as a chain bolted to a wall, its speed is 0. It has blindsight with a radius of 30 feet and is blind beyond that distance. When the animated object drops to 0 hit points, it reverts to its original object form, and any remaining damage carries over to its original object form.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">summon</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dancing Wave" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DANCING_WAVE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon a surging mass of water into existence at a point on the ground or in water within range. The mass of water remains cohesive and fills a 5-foot radius, though it is only 3 feet deep. The area is difficult terrain for any creature without a swimming speed.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action for the duration, you can move the wave up to 30 feet along the surface in any direction. If it enters a creature's space, that creature must make a Strength saving throw or take 2d6 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone. A creature automatically fails this saving throw if it is already prone. The wave can only slam into one creature on a turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjunction</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Decaying Touch" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DECAYING_TOUCH">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Melee</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You wreath your hand in necrotic decay, causing anything you touch to wither and die. Make a melee spell attack against a creature or object within range. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 necrotic damage and starts to flake and decay. The first time it takes damage from another source before the start of your next turn, it takes an additional 1d6 necrotic damage. Targets immune to diseases are immune to this effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">The both the initial and secondary damage of the spell increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">powdered remains of a dead animal</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Deglove Creature" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DEGLOVE_CREATURE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point at a creature within range, and attempt to make its skeleton rip free of its body. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. The target takes 7d10 + 7 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">If this damage kills the target, its flesh sloughs of its skeleton, collapsing into a pile. Its skeleton emerges and becomes a Skeleton (Basic Rules, pg. 152), hostile to all living creatures, and attacks the closest target.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a finger bone</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Devouring Darkness" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DEVOURING_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Dark tendrils burst out from you in all directions. Each creature of your choice within 20 feet must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 6d8 necrotic damage, and you can pull them in a straight line to an empty space within 5 feet of you. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is not pulled.</p>
            <p class="indent">You regain hit points equal to one quarter (rounded down) of the necrotic damage taken by all targets affected by the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Devour Shadow" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DEVOUR_SHADOW">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your shadow elongates into a horrifying abomination and attempts to consume the shadow of a creature you choose in range. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the target's shadow is devoured. It takes 6d6 necrotic damage and is magically weakened, subtracting 1d4 from its attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks for the duration, and adding 1d4 to your attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks for the duration. On a success, the target takes half as much damage and suffers no other effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">If either you or the target has no shadow, the spell fails. If the target's shadow is consumed, they have no shadow until the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell with a 5th-level spell slot or higher, you can target an additional creature for each spell slot level above 4th. The bonus you gain from consuming shadows does not increase beyond 1d4, even if you consume multiple shadows.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dig" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIG">
        <supports>Druid, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the end of your turn, you gain a burrowing speed of 30 feet. You can move through dirt, sand, or clay with this movement, and leave behind a tunnel equal to your size that remains stable for 1 minute (after which it may remain or collapse based on the properties of the ground moved through). You cannot move through stone (natural or constructed) with this movement.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">burrowing</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a mole's claw</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dimension Cutter" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIMENSION_CUTTER">
        <supports>Ranger, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You flourish the weapon used in the casting and sweep it through the air, slicing a rift through dimensions. Each creature in a 15-foot cone takes 6d6 force damage. This ignores total cover and strikes creatures in the ethereal plane as well as the material plane.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th Level or higher, it deals an additional 1d6 damage to each target for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (15-foot cone)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon with which you are proficient worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Divine Descent" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIVINE_DESCENT">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You call down a spectral angelic avatar which slowly descends from the sky toward a target point within range. The avatar fills a 30-foot-radius, 60-foot high cylinder with bright light. When you cast the spell and at the start of your next turn, you can choose to either heal all creatures within the light, restoring 4d8 hit points to creatures of your choice that are not undead or fiends within it, or burn all creatures within the light, forcing each one to make a Constitution saving throw, taking 4d8 radiant damage on a failed save or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of your turn on the third and final turn of the spell, the spell's effects are doubled, either restoring 8d8 hit points or dealing 8d8 radiant damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">heal</set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 3 rounds</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Divine Judgement" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIVINE_JUDGEMENT">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A brilliant sword of radiant energy forms above the target point and slams down in an explosion of divine power. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius, 30-foot high cylinder centered on the target point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 2d8 radiant damage, and 2d8 additional radiant damage if it is an undead or fiend. On a success, it takes half as much damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the base damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your DM uses alignment for creatures, they can optionally rule that the bonus damage applies all creature types as long as the creature is of the opposite moral alignment of the caster (evil to good or good to evil). As not all settings use strict alignment, this is a variant rule at the GM’s discretion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Disorient" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DISORIENT">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point at a creature you can see and flip its perception of reality. The target must pass a Wisdom saving throw or become disoriented. A disoriented creature has disadvantage on all attack rolls, and at the start of each of its turns, it moves 10 feet (up to its speed) in a random direction. Its speed then becomes zero until the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends, but if the target fails by 5 or more, it falls prone.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a möbius strip</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dispel Contruct" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DISPEL_CONTRUCT">
        <supports>Inventor, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to purge the magic animating a construct within range, rendering it inert. The target takes 4d10 force damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it becomes stunned for the duration, and if it has less than 50 hit points remaining, it is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Divide Self" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIVIDE_SELF">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an exact duplicate of yourself in an empty space you can see within 30 feet. At the start of each of your turns for the duration, you can switch places with your duplicate.</p>
            <p class="indent">The duplicate has all of your stats, abilities, and equipment (including magic items). It acts on your initiative and takes its own actions. You and the duplicate share concentration on this spell, and if either of you lose concentration, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your current hit points are divided between you and the duplicate, and you share all other resources and abilities (including limited-use items). Usage by either you or the duplicate depletes a resource for both of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your duplicate can take any action you can take, but it can deal a maximum of 15 damage on its turn. Any additional damage is reduced to 0, and damage applied to multiple targets is split between them equally until the maximum is reached.</p>
            <p class="indent">If either you or the duplicate is reduced to 0 hit points, the spell ends and you become the surviving copy. If you and the duplicate are both present when the spell ends, you decide which copy you become, and the other vanishes. Any items duplicated by the spell vanish.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you and the duplicate both start with 15 additional hit points (up to your current hit points prior to casting), and the maximum damage the duplicate can do during its turn increases by 10 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dragon Surge" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DRAGON_SURGE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You channel elemental power to form draconic wings, selecting one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. Each creature within 10 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw as the wings manifest, taking 2d8 damage of that chosen type on a failure, or half as much on a success. You gain a flying speed of 30 feet until the end of your turn, after which the wings fade away.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 and the flying speed increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire, cold, lightning, poison, acid</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dust Cyclone" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DUST_CYCLONE">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A small cyclone whips up at a point you can see on the ground within range. The cyclone is a 5-foot-radius, 30-foot-high cylinder centered on that point.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any creature that starts its turn within the radius of the dust cyclone or enters its radius for the first time during its turn must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d12 bludgeoning damage is pushed 5 feet away from the center. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage isn’t pushed.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can move the dust cyclone up 30 feet in any direction. The first time you pass the dust cyclone’s radius through a creature, that creature must make the saving throw against the dust cyclone’s damage and are pushed out its way on failure. You can continue to move the dust cyclone, but its strength is exhausted until the end of your turn and subsequent creatures an unaffected by it passing through them.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the dust cyclone moves over sand, dust, loose dirt, or small gravel, it sucks up the material and heavily obscures its radius until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjunction</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet (5-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pinch of dust</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Ripple" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_EARTH_RIPPLE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause the earth to deform at a point you can see within range. Every creature within 10 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. Choose one of the effects below, affecting each creature which fails its save.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Sink.</em></strong> A creature is pulled into the earth, taking 1d8 bludgeoning damage and reducing its movement speed to zero until it or another creature within 5 feet spends an action to dig it free.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Slam.</em></strong> A creature is pushed 5 feet in a direction of your choice by a wave of earth, taking 2d8 bludgeoning damage and falling prone.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Impale.</em></strong> A creature takes 4d8 piercing damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning, piercing</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Echoing Lance" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ECHOING_LANCE">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You emit a targeted burst of intense sonic energy at a creature within range. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 3d8 thunder damage and is stunned for the duration. On a success, it takes half as much damage and isn’t stunned.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends. On a failure, it takes an additional 1d8 thunder from the ongoing echoes of the sound.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Electric Arc" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELECTRIC_ARC">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You shoot a jolt of lightning at a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On hit, the target takes 1d8 primary lightning damage and an arc of lightning jumps from the target to another creature within 15 feet, using the same attack roll, dealing 1d4 secondary lightning damage on hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 primary and 1d4 secondary damage when you reach 5th level (2d8 and 2d4), 11th level (3d8 and 3d4), and 17th level (4d8 and 4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Electrify" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELECTRIFY">
        <supports>Occultist, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Melee</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You channel lightning into your hands. The next time you hit a creature with a melee attack (including a melee spell attack) before the start of your next turn, the target takes 1d12 lightning damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes stunned until the start of their next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell ends after dealing damage, or at the start of your next turn, whichever occurs first.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Electrocute" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELECTROCUTE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A massive arc of lightning leaps from your hand to a target you can see within range. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 4d12 lightning damage and is stunned until the start of your next turn. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t stunned.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d12 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Elemental Barrage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Ranger, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch of piece of ammunition and infuse it with chaotic elemental power. If that piece of ammunition is fired before the start of your next turn, it transforms into three elemental bolts, one each dealing fire, cold, and lightning damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Make a weapon attack roll for each elemental bolt. You can fire all three at the same target or at different targets within the weapon's range. On a hit, each bolt deals elemental damage equal to the attack's normal damage, but of its elemental damage type.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire, cold, lightning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ammunition</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Elemental Exhalation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_EXHALATION">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gather elemental power in your lungs, selecting one damage type out of acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison, and then exhale it in a mighty gust of energy. Each creature in a 20-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d8 damage of the chosen type, or half as much damage on a successful save.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cannot breathe, have no mouth, or your mouth is currently covered, the spell fails.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid, cold, fire, lighting, poison</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">20 foot cone</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a fragment of a dragon’s scale</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Elemental Orb" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_ORB">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You form an orb of power, molding it into an element of your choice. Select one damage type from acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. Make a ranged spell attack against a target you can see within range. On hit, the target takes 3d8 damage of the selected damage type.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Entomb" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ENTOMB">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to encase a Medium or smaller creature you can see within ice. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or become restrained in ice for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, it takes 1d8 cold damage and can make another Strength saving throw. On success, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the creature suffers an instance of at least 5 fire or bludgeoning damage while restrained, the ice breaks and the target is freed, ending the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ethereal Immolation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ETHEREAL_IMMOLATION">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You shroud a target in a luminous ethereal shroud which reacts violently to the presence of magic. For the duration, if the target casts a spell, it takes 2d4 force damage. This damage increases by 1d4 for each spell level of the spell cast (no additional damage for cantrips).</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if the target ends its turn while concentrating on a spell, it takes 1d4 force damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Erode" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ERODE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You blast a creature or object within range with a glob of acid. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 8d4 acid damage immediately and is covered in acid. On a success, the target takes half as much damage and is not covered in acid. While covered in acid, the target takes 2d4 acid damage at the end of each of its turns. The target or a creature within 5 feet of it can end this damage by using its action to clear away the acid.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage (both initial and later) increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">20 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Eyes of Immolation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_EYES_OF_IMMOLATION">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your eyes glow with fiery light before focusing on a creature you can see within range, causing a beam of fire to shoot from your eyes. The target creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 3d6 fire damage and is set ablaze, taking 1d6 damage at the end of each of its turns until it or another creature within 5 feet of it spends an action to douse the flames. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and is not set ablaze.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Explosive Deflection" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_EXPLOSIVE_DEFLECTION">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You release an explosive blast of energy to deflect an attack. Roll 2d6 and reduce the attack's damage by the result. If the attack's damage was reduced to 0, and it was a melee attack, the attacker takes the remainder of your dice roll as thunder damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the dice rolled increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pinch of black powder</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fall" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FALL">
        <supports>Inventor, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You alter gravity for yourself, reorienting which way is down for you until the end of your turn. You can pick any direction to fall (as if under the effect of gravity), falling up to 500 feet before the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you collide with something during this time, you take falling damage as normal. You can control your fall as you would normally by holding onto objects, or move along a surface according to your new orientation until your turn ends and gravity returns to normal.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Field of Stars" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FIELD_OF_STARS">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause 5 star-like motes of light to spring forth at points you can see within range. Each mote of light sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. If a creature moves within 5 feet of a mote on a turn or ends its turn within 5 feet of one, the mote explodes in a brilliant flash, dealing 4d12 radiant damage to all creatures within 5 feet of it before fading away. If multiple motes explode at once, a creature hit by more than one only takes damage once.</p>
            <p class="indent">For the duration of the spell, while you have any motes of light remaining, you can use your action to rearrange the remaining motes, placing them anywhere within range. This movement cannot cause them to detonate.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the range increases by 10 feet and you create one additional mote of light for each slot level about 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Final Flame" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FINAL_FLAME">
        <supports>Cleric, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You place an ember of divine flame within a creature, which lies dormant until it is triggered. It activates if its carrier is reduced to 0 hit points or uses its bonus action to activate it.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the ember is activated, it explodes, causing all creatures within 20 feet except the carrier to make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 8d6 radiant damage. On a success, it takes half as much damage. The ember's carrier regains 8d6 hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant, heal</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a phoenix's feather</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fire Cyclone" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FIRE_CYCLONE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You whip up a cyclone of roaring flame at a point on the ground you can see, occupying a 10-foot-radius, 30-foot-high cylinder. Any creature inside the spell when you cast it or entering its area for first time on a turn must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, it takes 3d6 fire damage and is flung up to half the cyclone's height, landing 15 feet outside the cyclone in a randomly determined horizontal direction. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and is not flung.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature starts its turn outside the cyclone but within 30 feet of its center, it feels the cyclone's pull and must spend 2 feet (or 3 feet if it is flying) of movement for every 1 foot it moves away from the cyclone.</p>
            <p class="indent">For the duration of the spell, you can use your action to move the cyclone up to 30 feet in any direction along the ground.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the cyclone's damage increases by 1d6 and its height increases by 5 feet for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pinch of ashes from a forest fire</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fireburst Mine" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FIREBURST_MINE">
        <supports>Inventor, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You set a magical trap, infusing explosive magic into an object. You can set the item to detonate when someone comes within 5 feet of it, or at a verbal command by you. You can issue this command as an action or as a reaction when you see a creature move within 20 feet of a mine, detonating every mine keyed to the verbal command simultaneously</p>
            <p class="indent">When the magic trap detonates, each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on the item must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 5d8 fire damage on a failure, or half as much damage on a success. If a creature is in the area of effect of more than one fireburst mine during a turn, it takes half damage from any mines beyond the first.</p>
            <p class="indent">A magical mine must be set at least 5 feet away from every other mine, and cannot be moved once placed; any attempt to move it results in it detonating. The caster can permanently disarm a mine as an action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a tiny nonmagical item, which is destroyed when the spell ends</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fissure" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FISSURE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You rend the earth asunder in a 60-foot long, 5-foot wide line, targeting an area of dirt, sand, or rock at least 10 feet deep.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each creature within that line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature falls into the crevice, which snaps shut and begins to crush it. The creature takes 6d10 bludgeoning damage and is buried in 10 feet of rubble. A creature without a burrowing speed can spend 25 feet of movement to dig itself out, reappearing at the location it stood before the spell. A creature that ends its turn buried takes an additional 1d10 bludgeoning damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fists of Fire" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FISTS_OF_FIRE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause your fists to erupt in flames. For the duration, your fists become a set of simple natural weapons that deal 1d6 fire damage. You are proficient in these weapons, and they have the Light property. For the duration, any flammable object you attempt to hold catches fire. If you end your turn grappling another creature with your hands, it takes 1d4 fire damage. You can end the spell early (no action required).</p>
            <p class="indent">The damage this spell does to grappled targets increases by 1d4 at 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Flamethrower" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FLAMETHROWER">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You release a stream of fire from your hands, filling a 30-foot long, 10-foot wide line with a continual gout of flame. Any creature in the area when you cast the spell or entering the area before the start of your next turn must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 fire damage on a failure or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action on your subsequent turns for the duration, you can release a new line of fire with the same effect.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Flash Freeze" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FLASH_FREEZE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A freezing wind ripples outward. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 4d8 cold damage and is restrained by ice until the start of your next turn. On a success, it takes half as much damage and isn’t restrained.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot cone)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Flickering Strikes" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FLICKERING_STRIKES">
        <supports>Ranger, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You brandish the weapon used in the casting before disappearing, instantly teleporting to and striking up to 5 targets within range. Make a melee weapon attack against each target. On a hit, a target takes the normal weapon damage from the attack, plus an additional 6d6 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can then teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of any target of the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon you are proficient with worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fling" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FLING">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You manipulate gravity around one Large or smaller creature. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, you can fling it 40 feet straight up or 20 feet in any other direction.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you fling the target upward, it immediately falls, taking 4d6 falling damage and landing prone. If you fling it in any other direction, it takes 2d6 damage and lands prone. If this movement would be stopped early by a creature or object, both the target and whatever it collides with takes 3d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Force Blade" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORCE_BLADE">
        <supports>supports</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an oversized blade of scintillating energy in your hand. For the duration, you can sweep the blade as an action through one or two adjacent creatures within range, automatically dealing force damage equal to 2d12 + your spellcasting modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast it using a 5th or 6th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 3d12. When you cast it using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases to 4d12.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (10 feet)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Force Bolt" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORCE_BOLT">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You hurl a mote of arcane energy at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d4 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 2d4 when you reach 5th level (4d4), 11th level (6d4), and 17th level (8d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of Familiar" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_FAMILIAR">
        <supports>Occultist, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You assume the form of the familiar that provided the material component to the spell. This transformation lasts for the duration or until you drop to 0 hit points or die. Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the chosen creature, though you retain your alignment and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores.</p>
            <p class="indent">You assume the hit points and hit dice of the new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn’t reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren’t knocked unconscious. You can use an action to revert to your normal form at any time.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are limited in the actions you can perform by the nature of your new form, and you can’t speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech. Your gear melds into the new form. You cannot activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of your familiar such as fur, feathers, or scales, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of Fire" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_FIRE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become elemental fire, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You are immune to fire damage.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain. The first time on a turn you enter the space of another creature, it takes 2d6 fire damage.</li>
                <li>If a creature within 5 feet hits you with a melee attack, it takes 2d6 fire damage.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to create a line of fire 30 feet long and 5 feet wide extending from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 6d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation, fire</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of Ice" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_ICE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You freeze over, taking on a form of elemental ice. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You are immune to cold damage.</li>
                <li>You can move across difficult terrain created by ice or snow without spending extra movement.</li>
                <li>The ground in a 15-foot radius around you is icy and is difficult terrain for creatures other than you. The radius moves with you.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to create a 30-foot cone of freezing wind extending from your outstretched hand in a direction you choose. Each creature in the cone must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that fails its save against this effect has its speed halved until the start of your next turn.</li>
                <li>During your turn, if you roll cold damage, you gain temporary hit points equal to one die rolled (your choice).</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation, cold</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Form of Stone" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_STONE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become made of stone. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move across difficult terrain made of earth or stone without spending extra movement. You can move through solid earth or stone as if it was air and without destabilizing it, but you can’t end your movement there. If you do so, you are ejected to the nearest unoccupied space, this spell ends, and you are stunned until the end of your next turn.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to call spikes of stone to raise from the ground. All creatures of your choice within 15 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. Its space becomes difficult terrain either way.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of the Elements" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_THE_ELEMENTS">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the duration of the spell, you gain the benefits of the form of fire, form of ice, form of stone, form of water, and form of wind spells.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation</set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of Water" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_WATER">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a surge of elemental water. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain; the first time you move through a Large or smaller creature, it must pass a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to unleash a blast of water 15 feet long and 5 feet wide extending from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Strength saving throw. A creature takes 5d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone on a failed save, or half as much and isn’t knocked prone on a successful one.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation, bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Form of Wind" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FORM_OF_WIND">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a gust of elemental wind. Until the spell ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have a flying speed of 60 feet.</li>
                <li>You can move through and occupy the space of other creatures, and you ignore difficult terrain.</li>
                <li>You are invisible.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to unleash a powerful blast of wind in a 30 foot cone. Each creature in the cone must make a Strength saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage and is knocked 15 feet away from you on a failed save, or takes half as much damage and isn’t knocked backward on a successful one.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">transformation</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Freeze" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_FREEZE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You instill a deadly chill into your hand. Make a melee spell attack against a creature you can reach. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 cold damage, and its speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Gale Bolt" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GALE_BOLT">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A blast of concentrated wind streaks toward a creature of your choice within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, it takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage, and if it is Large or smaller, it is knocked 10 feet away from you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell lot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Gale Shot" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GALE_SHOT">
        <supports>Rangers</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a piece of ammunition or weapon with the thrown property, imbuing it with the power of a hurricane for the duration. The first time you attack with the empowered item, it is propelled with hurricane force. On a hit, the target takes an additional 4d8 damage from the attack and is knocked backwards 30 feet. Any creature the target collides with takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage. On a miss, the target takes half as much damage and is not knocked back</p>
            <p class="indent">Once an attack has been made with the piece of ammunition or weapon, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level, the shot deals an additional 1d8 damage and the target is knocked backwards an additional 10 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ammunition or a weapon worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Geyser" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GEYSER">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause a massive eruption of water to blast upwards from the ground at a point within range. Each creature within 10 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 4d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked 60 feet up into the air. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage, and is instead knocked either 10 feet away from the point or 10 feet upward (its choice).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ghost Step" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GHOST_STEP">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become briefly ethereal and intangible. For the duration, you can move in any direction and do not fall. You can move through creatures, objects, walls, terrain, and effects as if they were not there. You can only pass through magical objects if they do not block ethereal transit. While you are intangible, you are immune to all damage except force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of your next turn, you become tangible again in your current space. If the space is occupied, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and take force damage equal to twice the number of feet you are forced to move. If you are in the air and cannot fly, you fall to the ground.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Glacial Crash" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GLACIAL_CRASH">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A huge chunk of ice appears in the sky before crashing down at a point within range before shattering into an explosion of ice. Creatures within 30 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, a creature takes 6d6 cold damage, and if it was within 10 feet of the target point, it takes an additional 6d8 bludgeoning damage. On success, a creature takes half as much cold damage, and half as much bludgeoning damage (if applicable).</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s area of effect becomes difficult terrain until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Gravity Surge" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GRAVITY_SURGE">
        <supports>Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a crushing field of gravity in a 15 radius sphere. Each creature within the area must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage and falls prone. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is not knocked prone. Creatures that are not on the ground make this save with disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Grip of the Dead" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GRIP_OF_THE_DEAD">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You channel unholy strength into your hand as you attempt to grab a creature you can reach. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or become restrained by your deathly grasp. As an action on its turn, it can attempt to escape using a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against your Spell Save DC.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of the creature's turn while you maintain the grip and the spell, it takes 1d8 necrotic damage. You regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Grasping Roots" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GRASPING_ROOTS">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A twisting burst of roots launch from your hand, reaching to grab a Large or smaller target. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, it is pulled 20 feet in a direction of your choice. On a success, the target is only pulled 5 feet. A creature can choose to fail this save.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you move a creature an additional 5 feet for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">displacement</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Heavenly Ray" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_HEAVENLY_RAY">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A golden pillar of celestial radiance shines down in a 10-foot radius, 60-foot-high cylinder centered on a point you can see within range. Until the spell ends, the cylinder is filled with bright light and sheds dim light for 10 feet in all directions from it.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature enters the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, the celestial radiance infuses its body with positive energy. If the creature is not an undead or construct, it regains 2d8 hit points and gains 2d8 temporary hit points. If it is a construct, the light has no effect. If it is undead, it instead takes 2d8 radiant damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The first time a creature is healed by this spell, it is healed without restriction; every subsequent time a creature is healed by this spell, it can't be healed above half its maximum hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can move the pillar up to 60 feet in any direction.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">heal, radiant</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Heavy Blow" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_HEAVY_BLOW">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You impart great heft to an unarmed strike or weapon you are holding. The first time you hit with a melee weapon attack using that weapon before the start of your next turn, your blow strikes with great force, and the attack deals an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage to the target and must succeed a Constitution saving throw, or becomes dazed until the start of its next turn. While dazed this way, it cannot take reactions, and attacks against it have advantage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a weapon or unarmed strike that does bludgeoning damage</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hellfire Pit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_HELLFIRE_PIT">
        <supports>Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You open a pit to hell beneath the feet of your foes. A supernatural void opens in a 10-foot radius, 10-foot deep pit opens around a point you can see within range.</p>
            <p class="indent">Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On success, they can move 5 feet outside the radius of the spell. If they cannot move 5 feet out of the radius of the spell (such as having no path or insufficient movement speed), they automatically fail the saving throw. Creatures that fall their saving throw fall to the bottom of the bit (taking 1d6 bludgeoning damage and falling prone). The floor of the pit is a blazing inferno of hell. Creatures that start their turn in the pit take 4d6 fire damage and 4d6 necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The pit is difficult to escape, voraciously drawing creatures caught in to the depths of hell with strong winds, roaring fires, and infernal chains. A creature can spend 20 feet of movement (or 10 if they a flying or climbing speed) to attempt to escape the pit, making a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. On success, they escape. On failure, fall back to the floor of the pit and their movement speed becomes 0 until the start of their next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, the supernatural void to hell closes, and all creatures in the pit are deposited on the ground where the pit opened prone.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire, bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hungering Void" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_HUNGERING_VOID">
        <supports>Occultist, Warlock, Spellblade Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gesture at a point you can see within range and summon a 20-foot radius sphere of blackness, a void of magical darkness which attempts to devour whatever enters. Darkvision cannot penetrate it, and no light can illuminate the darkness unless caused by a spell of a higher level.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that starts its turn within the void must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 2d6 cold damage and 2d6 necrotic damage, and its speed is reduced by 5 feet to a minimum of 5 feet. This speed reduction stacks with successive failures, and ends once the creature starts its turn outside the void. On a success, the creature takes half as much damage and its speed is not reduced.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the necrotic and cold damage both increase by 1d6, and the speed reduction increases to 10 feet for each failed save.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hurricane Slash" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_HURRICANE_SLASH">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You condense wind into a razor sharp blast that shreds a 30-foot-long 5-foot-wide line. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d8 slashing damage on a failed save or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can create an additional line of effect. A creature in the area of more than one slash is affected only once.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ice Arrow" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ICE_ARROW">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a shard of ice before hurling it at a target you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack. On hit, the target takes 2d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier cold damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ice Spike" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ICE_SPIKE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a lance of ice which shoots up from the ground to impale a creature you can see within range. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 4d8 piercing damage and 4d8 cold damage. On a success, it only takes the cold damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th or 7th level, you can create a second spike. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, you can create a third spike. Additional spikes can target the same or different creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ice Weapon" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ICE_WEAPON">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a weapon of magical ice in your hand, which takes the form of one of the weapons listed below. You are proficient with it, and while wielding it, you can change its form as a bonus action. If you lose or discard the weapon, you can reform it in your hand as a bonus action.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Weapon</td><td>Damage</td><td>Properties</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Ice Spear</td><td>1d6</td><td>Thrown (30/90)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ice Sword</td><td>1d6</td><td>Versatile (d8)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ice Lance</td><td>1d8</td><td>Two-Handed, Reach</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ice Hammer</td><td>1d10</td><td>Two-Handed, Heavy</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ice Dagger</td><td>1d4</td><td>Finesse, Thrown (30/90)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p>Regardless of its form, the weapon deals cold damage. You can end the spell early, letting the weapon melt to a harmless splash of water (no action required). You can have up to three ice weapons formed from this spell at a time. If you form a fourth, the first melts away.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a drop of water that was once snow</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusionary Dart" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ILLUSIONARY-DART">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create and throw an illusionary dart at a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack. On hit, they take 1d8 psychic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The number of darts you can throw with this spell increases when you reach 5th level (2 darts), 11th (3 darts), and 17th level (4 darts). You can direct the dart at the same target or at different ones. Make a separate attack roll for each dart.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">psychic</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusionary Fireball" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ILLUSIONARY_FIREBALL">
        <supports>Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A bright streak flashes from your fingertip to a point you can see within range before blossoming into a 20-foot radius illusionary explosion. Each creature of your choice in the area must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 6d6 psychic damage. On a success, a creature realizes the fire is illusionary and takes no damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can choose to make illusion an explosion of ice, lightning, or pure force energy.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em></em></strong>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">psychic</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something that looks like bat guano</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusionary Pit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ILLUSIONARY_PIT">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a 5-foot radius illusory pit at a point you can see on the ground. Each creature within the area when the spell is cast must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or believe it has fallen into the pit. It falls prone, cannot stand up, and cannot see beyond the radius of the pit.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature can spend its action to attempt to climb out of the pit, repeating its saving throw. On a success, it spends all of its movement to stand up and then realizes the pit is an illusion, ending the spell for it. On a failure, it continues to believe it is stuck in the pit. An affected creature can move within the spaces covered by the pit.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature with a flying speed automatically succeeds on its saving throw. Each time a creature under the effect takes damage, it can repeat its saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast the spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the pit increases by 5 feet for each level above 1st, to a maximum of a 20 feet with a 4th-level spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Imbue Luck" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IMBUE_LUCK">
        <supports>Inventor</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a weapon or worn item and imbue luck into it for the duration. If you target a weapon, its wielder can roll an additional d20 when making an attack (deciding after the roll, but before the outcome is determined). The creature chooses which of the d20s to use.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you target a worn item, the wearer can roll a d20 when attacked, choosing whether the attack uses the original d20 result or this one.</p>
            <p class="indent">After the extra die is rolled, the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a four-leaf clover</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Immutability" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IMMUTABILITY">
        <supports>Cleric, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You assume an immutable form. You become immune to other transmutation spells or magical effects that would alter your form.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you don’t move during your turn, you gain advantage on Strength or Constitution saving throws made before the start of your next turn, and cannot be moved or knocked down against your will.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the spell is active, as a reaction to taking bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage you can gain resistance to that damage type (Including the triggering damage) until the end of your next turn, but your movement speed becomes zero until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Impact" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IMPACT">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You impart great force into a target you touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. On hit, the target takes 1d10 bludgeoning damage, and is knocked 5 feet directly away from you.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Induce Headache" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INDUCE_HEADACHE">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You inflict a splitting headache on one creature you can see within range. The target takes 1 psychic damage at the start each of its turns and has disadvantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain Concentration and Intelligence ability checks. Creatures with Intelligence 5 or less suffer no effects from this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">psychic</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bad pun written on a scrap of parchment</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Infernal Shackles" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INFERNAL_SHACKLES">
        <supports>Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Chains of burning black iron spring from the ground and attempt to bind a creature you can see within range. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, it takes 3d6 fire damage and its speed is reduced to 0 for the duration. On a success, it takes half as much damage and is not bound.</p>
            <p class="indent">The target must repeat its saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, the chains break and the spell ends for that target. On a failure, it remains bound and takes an additional 2d6 fire damage as it is seared by the chains.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell with a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target an additional creature for each spell slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a link from a chain burned in a fire that killed at least one creature</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Infinite Edge" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INFINITE_EDGE">
        <supports>Ranger, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You instill a magical sharpness to a weapon you're holding or a natural weapon you possess, which must deal piercing or slashing damage. You have advantage on the next attack roll you make with it before the start of your next turn, and if the attack hits it deals an additional 1d10 damage of the weapon's type.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a weapon or natural weapon that deals piercing or slashing damage</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Instant Bulwark" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INSTANT_BULWARK">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause a 15-foot-long, 10-foot-tall, 6-inch thick wall of earth to erupt from the ground in an empty space you can see within range. The wall grants total cover and blocks any damage originating from the far side of the wall. It blocks ranged attacks and any area-of-effect spells or magical effects with areas intersecting the wall.</p>
            <p class="indent">The wall has hit points equal to 4d10 + your spellcasting modifier. It takes all damage it blocks, even if that damage normally only affects creatures, but it only suffers the blocked damage one time even if it protects multiple creatures. If it is reduced to 0 hit points, it crumbles to dust and any excess damage is dealt as normal. If the wall is not destroyed, it crumbles at the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the wall has 1d10 additional hit points and is 5 feet longer for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you can take when a creature within range takes damage from a ranged attack or area effect</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Instant Counter" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INSTANT_COUNTER">
        <supports>Bard, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You vanish, teleporting to an empty space within 5 feet of the creature that damaged you, and immediately make a weapon attack against them with the weapon used in the spell’s casting.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, if your attack hits, it deals 1d8 additional force damage for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take in response to being damaged by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Invest Life" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_INVEST_LIFE">
        <supports>Cleric, Occultist, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You draw on your life force to invest some of your vital essence into another creature you can see within range. You take 4d8 necrotic damage, which can’t be reduced in any way, and one creature of your choice that you can see within range regains a number of hit points equal to twice the necrotic damage you take.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">heal</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Iron Garden" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IRON_GARDEN">
        <supports>Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Iron spikes lance up from the ground, impaling every creature within 20 feet of you. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 6d8 piercing damage and its speed drops to 0 until the end of its next turn. On a success, it takes half as much damage and its speed is not reduced.</p>
            <p class="indent">Until the start of your next turn, when a creature moves into or within the area, it takes 1d8 piercing damage for every 5 feet it travels. At the start of your next turn, the spikes rust away to dust.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Iron Wind Strike" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_IRON_WIND_STRIKE">
        <supports>Ranger, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You flourish the weapon used in the casting and then vanish to strike like the wind. Choose up to three creatures you can see within range. Make a melee weapon attack against each target. On a hit, a target takes 3d8 damage of the weapon’s damage type.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can then teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of any of the targets.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd Level or higher, it deals an additional 1d8 damage to each target on hit for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (15-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon with which you are proficient worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Jumping Jolt" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_JUMPING_JOLT">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You release an arc of lighting at a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack roll against the target. On a hit, it takes 4d12 lightning damage, and you can cause the spell to jump to another target within 20 feet of the first, making a new attack roll for the new target. The spell cannot hit the same target twice, or jump to a target outside the spell's range. The spell can jump a maximum of five times.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a miss, a target takes half as much damage and the spell does not jump to a new target.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the starting damage increases by 1d12 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Karmic Reflection" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_KARMIC_REFLECTION">
        <supports>Cleric, Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You place a magical binding on a creature you can see within range. Until the start of your next turn, anytime that creature deals damage with its action, bonus action, or reaction, it takes radiant damage equal to the damage dealt, up to a maximum of 10 damage. The target is aware of spell's effects. After reflecting 10 damage, spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the maximum damage increases by 10 for each spell slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a broken shard of a mirror</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Killing Curse" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_KILLING_CURSE">
        <supports>Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You curse a target to die. Its current and maximum hit points are reduced by 3d10 + 10. If this causes the creature to have 0 hit points, it dies.</p>
            <p class="indent">For the duration, the target cannot regain hit points except from a spell of a higher level than this one, and any death saving throw it rolls is automatically considered a 1.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of each of the target's turns, it makes a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, its current and maximum hit points are reduced by 1d10 + 10. On a success, the spell ends. A creature’s maximum hit points are restored when it finishes a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lightning Charged" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_LIGHTNING_CHARGED">
        <supports>Inventor</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You charge a creature you touch with sparking electricity, causing it no damage but making its touch dangerous for others. Every time the target hits another creature with a melee attack or a spell with a range of touch, is hit with a melee attack by another creature, or ends its turn while grappling or being grappled by another creature, the other creature takes 1d6 lightning damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once this spell has discharged 6 times (dealing up to 6d6 damage), the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell can discharge 2 additional times (dealing 2d6 more total damage) before the spell ends for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of metal once used in a lightning rod</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lightning Shot" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_LIGHTNING_SHOT">
        <supports>Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a piece of ammunition or a weapon with the thrown property, imbuing it with crackling lightning for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">The first time you attack with the empowered item, it transforms into a bolt of lightning, blasting out from you in a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide. Make one weapon attack, applying the result against every creature in the line. This attack deals 4d8 lightning damage on a hit, and half as much damage on a miss. This damage roll doesn't add any modifiers or bonuses associated with weapon attacks. The lightning ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once an attack has been made with the piece of ammunition or weapon, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each level above 3rd, up to a maximum of 6d8 at 5th level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ammunition or a weapon worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lightning Tendril" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_LIGHTNING_TENDRIL">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Crackling beams of blue energy leap from your hands. For the duration of the spell, as an action, you can direct them toward a creature within range, dealing 1d12 lightning damage to that creature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a 2nd- or 3rd-level spell slot, the damage increases to 2d12 and the range increases to 30 feet. When you cast it using a 4th- or 5th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 3d12 and the range increases to 60 feet. When you cast it using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases to 4d12 and the range increases to 120 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20 feet)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>

<!-- 
<element name="Spell Name" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_SPELL NAME">
        <supports>supports</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">level</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">range</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

<p class="indent"><strong><em></em></strong></p>
    
    -->