<elements>
    <info>
        <name>KibblesTasty SPells</name>
        <description></description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Acid Bubble" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACID_BUBBLE">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a bubble of acid that floats to the target point before bursting in a shower of acid. Each creature and object within 5 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 3d4 acid damage, or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 2d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 action</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Acid Rain" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACID_RAIN">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Acid rain begins falling within a 40-foot-radius, 60-foot-high cylinder centered on a point you choose within range. When a creature moves into the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 6d4 acid damage and is covered in acid. On a success, a creature takes half the initial damage and is not covered in acid.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature takes 3d4 acid damage if it ends its turn while covered in acid. The target or a creature within 5 feet of it can end this damage by using its action to clear away the acid.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Acidic Pit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ACIDIC_PIT">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You open a pit filled with acid at a point within range. Each creature within 10 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it falls 5 feet into a pit of acid below, taking 6d4 + 6 acid damage. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage from the flooding acid and can use its reaction to move up to its movement speed to the closest point outside of the area. If it cannot take a reaction or reach a safe space, it automatically fails its saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature ends its turn in the pit, it takes 2d4 acid damage. The acid in the pit remains potent for 1 minute, after which it turns to vile sludge that deals no further damage. The pit remains filled with sludge until filled or cleared.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aero Barrage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AERO_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create four lances of rapidly spinning condensed wind and hurl them at targets within range. You can direct the lances at one target or different ones.</p>
            <p class="indent">Make a ranged spell attack for each lance. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 slashing damage and is knocked 10 feet backwards.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you create one additional lance for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aether Lance" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AETHER_LANCE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gather raw aether in your hand and expel it in a lance of power, forming a line 30 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in the line takes 8d4 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aether Storm" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AETHER_STORM">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a storm of aether, erupting from a point of your choice within range. The aether storm fills a 10-foot radius, 40-foot-high cylinder. When the storm appears, each creature within its area takes 8d4 force damage. When a creature enters the storm or moves within it, it takes 2d4 force damage for every 5 feet it travels, and whenever a creature ends its turn in the storm it takes an additional 8d4 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your subsequent turns, you can move the storm up to 15 feet in any direction and cause it to fling forth a hail of force bolts that seek out up to 3 targets of your choice within 15 feet of the storm. Each target takes 3d4 + 3 force damage from the bolts.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage dealt when the storm is cast, when a creature ends its turn in the storm, or when a creature is struck by a force bolt increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Alacrity" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ALACRITY">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the start of your next turn, your speed is doubled, you gain a +2 bonus to AC, you have advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and you gain an additional action. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are under the effect of haste, you gain no benefit from this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aldricor's Elemental Rebuke" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ALDRICORS_ELEMENTAL_REBUKE">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Occultist, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You manipulate some of the incoming elemental energy, harnessing its power in your hand. The damage you take from the triggering attack or effect is cut in half. You can then hurl the energy back at the creature that damaged you if it is within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 1d8 damage of the triggering type on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">reaction</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Angelic Slash" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANGELIC_SLASH">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon a giant spectral angel that appears around you before crashing its greatsword down in a line. All creatures in a line 30 feet long and 5 feet wide in a direction of your choice must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 5d8 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature takes an additional 1d8 damage if it is undead or a fiend.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">radiant</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Animate Shadow" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANIMATE_SHADOW">
        <supports>Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Targeting a creature you can see within range, you bring its shadow to life under your control. If the creature has a challenge rating above 3 or has no shadow (either due to its nature or from the lack of a light source to cast one) the spell fails. Creatures without a challenge rating are immune to this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Otherwise, a copy of the creature is created using its game statistics in a space adjacent to the creature (on the opposite side as the nearest bright light). The shadow has no legendary actions, legendary resistance, and cannot cast spells. The shadow has hit points equal to half the target’s hit points, and it looks like a mirrored version of the creature it was summoned from, formed from inky black smoke. The shadow is resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical sources while in darkness. The shadow is vulnerable to all damage while in bright light, and always vulnerable to fire, lightning, and radiant damage. If the shadow is killed, the target creature it was summoned from casts no shadows for the next 8 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">The shadow acts immediately after the target's turn, and without further direction it attempts to follow and takes the Attack action against the target. As a reaction to the shadow starting its turn, you can exert control over it and cause it to move and take its action as you direct.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels. </i></strong>When you cast this spell using a 5th- or 6th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating of the target increases to 4. When you cast it using a 7th- or 8th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating increases to 5. When you cast it using a 9th-level spell slot, the maximum challenge rating increases to CR 6.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">summon</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a smoked stained mirror</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Anvil Drop" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ANVIL_DROP">
        <supports>Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure an anvil 500 feet above a point you can see. At initiative count 0 (losing ties) on the next round, the anvil hits the ground. Each creature within 5 feet of the target point must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it moves to the closest unoccupied space outside of the radius. If no space is available or a creature cannot move, it automatically fails. On a failure, a creature takes 10d10 + 10 bludgeoning damage. Creatures within 20 feet of the target point take 4d4 thunder damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the path of the anvil (directly above the target point) is interrupted, the creature or object above it is hit first. If the creature or object is killed or destroyed, the anvil continues, though the damage dealt is subtracted from the final impact damage of the anvil.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the anvil deals less than 80 damage, the anvil survives the impact, and is an anvil of moderate quality.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> When cast with a 9th-level spell slot, the range of the spell becomes 120 miles, though you must still be able to see the target (such as via scrying).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Ablation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_ABLATION">
        <supports>Inventor, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a piece of worn armor or clothing and imbue it with magic. For the duration, the wearer gains 4 temporary hit points. If these temporary hit points are exhausted, the creature gains 1 fewer temporary hit points at the start of its next turn. When the temporary hit points would reach 0, the spell ends. Temporary hit points gained from this spell are lost when the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><i>At Higher Levels.</i></strong> The initial temporary hit points increase by 1 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">temporary hit points</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Conduit" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_CONDUIT">
        <supports>Sorcerer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You tap directly into the arcane weave. For the duration, you have resistance to all damage from magical sources besides force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of each of your turns while tapped into this power, you and all creatures with 5 feet of you take 1d6 Force damage. The damage increases by 1d6 each turn to a maximum of 4d6 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Weapon" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_WEAPON">
        <supports>Inventor, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a weapon and imbue it with magic. For the duration, the weapon counts as a magical weapon and all damage dealt by it becomes force damage. When you cast this on a weapon with the ammunition property, the weapon doesn't consume ammunition when fired, and does not need to be reloaded.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using spell slot of 3rd or 4th level, the duration becomes hours. When you use a spell slot of 5th level or higherthe duration becomes 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcanist's Sword" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANISTS_SWORD">
        <supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a glowing sword-shaped plane of force that hovers within range for the duration. When the sword appears and as a bonus action on subsequent turns, you can give the sword one of the following commands.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Attack:</em></strong> The sword moves up to 20 feet toward a creature and makes a melee spell attack against it. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 3d10 + your spellcasting ability modifier</li>
                <li><strong><em>Guard:</em></strong> The sword moves up 20 feet into a creature’s space and grants the creature half cover as it attempts to deflect incoming attacks. The first time a hostile creature comes within 5 feet of the sword, the sword makes a melee spell attack against that creature. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 3d10 + your spellcasting ability modifier. The sword cannot attack again until you command it again</li>
                <li><strong><em>Whirl:</em></strong> The sword moves up to 20 feet toward a point and then begins to spin in a deadly whirl. A creature that starts in the sword’s space or passes within 5 feet of the sword on its turn must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 3d10 force damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a miniature platinum sword with a grip and pommel of copper and zinc, worth 250 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arctic Aura" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCTIC_AURA">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the duration you unleash a freezing aura. Any creature starting its turn within 20 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 2d8 cold damage and its speed is reduced to 0 until the start of its next turn. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage and its speed halved.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action on each of your turns for the duration, you can actively control the aura, excluding a number of creatures in the area up to your spellcasting modifier from the effects until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arctic Breath" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCTIC_BREATH">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A line of freezing arctic wind 30 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 2d8 cold damage and its speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't slowed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, slow</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Avalanche" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AVALANCHE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause the earth to ripple, triggering an avalanche of rock and stone to surge forward in a line 60 feet long and 15 feet wide. The length of the line is doubled if cast on a steeply sloped surface. Each creature caught in the surging tumble of rocks must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 6d10 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone. On a failure by 5 or more, it is stunned until the end of its next turn, and on a failure by 10 or more it is moved to the closest free space at the end of the line created by the spell. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and suffers none of the spell’s other effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell creates a 15 by 15 foot area of difficult terrain at the end of the line created by the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 6th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Awaken Rope" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_AWAKEN_ROPE">
        <supports>Bard, Inventor, Occultist, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can touch a rope of 10 to 60 feet in length and issue it a single command, selecting from the following options.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong><em>Bind.</em></strong> The rope attempts to bind a creature of your choice within 20 feet of you. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw or become restrained until it is freed. A creature can use its action to make a DC 10 Strength check, freeing itself or another creature within its reach on a success. Dealing 5 slashing damage to the rope (AC 10) also frees the creature without harming it, ending the effect and destroying the rope.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Fasten.</em></strong> The rope flies up 60 feet and ties one end of itself to an object or surface that a rope could be tied to, before becoming inanimate again, hanging from the object.</li>
                <li><strong><em>Grab.</em></strong> The rope lashes out at an object within its length and grabs one Small or smaller object that is not being worn by a creature, pulling it back to your hand. If the object is being carried by a creature, the creature can make a Strength saving throw. On a success, the object is not pulled.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target a chain instead of a rope. It has the same available actions, but it has a DC 15, an AC of 15, and resistance to slashing damage when taking the Bind action.</p>
            <p class="indent">When cast with a spell slot of 3rd level or higher targeting a rope, that rope is magically imbued for 1 minute, gaining an DC of 15, an AC 20, and 20 hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">level</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">10 to 60 feet of cord or rope, worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Baba's Walking Hut" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BABAS_WALKING_HUT">
        <supports>Occultist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a hut, cabin, or other building no more than 15 feet by 15 feet by 10 feet. On completion of the spell, the building grows legs large enough to support it, as well as the structural integrity needed stand and move, and becomes a gargantuan creature. It has 250 hit points, an AC of 12, and a walking speed of 20 feet. If it drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">On your turn, you can direct it to move (no action required) and it will continue to move as directed until you direct it to stop or reaches its destination. It can take no actions, but if it walks over a Large or smaller creature, you can direct it to attempt to step on that creature, and that creature must succeed a Dexterity saving throw, or take 2d10 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast this spell on the same building every day for a year, the spell lasts until dispelled, or you cast it on another building.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a chicken leg</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bad Blood" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BAD_BLOOD">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to corrupt the blood of a creature you can see within range. Creatures without blood are immune to this effect. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it takes 1d12 poison damage and becomes poisoned for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target. On a failure, it takes an additional 1d4 poison damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target an additional creature for each slot level above 2nd. All targets must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">poison</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of rotten meat</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Beam of Annihilation" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BEAM_OF_ANNIHILATION">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a beam of pure energy, creating a line of power 60 feet long and 10 feet wide, which persists until the start of your next turn. When you cast the spell, choose between cold, fire, force, or lightning damage for the beam. Any creature starting its turn in the beam must make a Dexterity saving throw. It takes 8d8 damage of the beam’s type on a failure or half as much on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">While you are concentrating on this spell, your speed is 0. At the start of each of your turns, you can use your action to maintain the beam in place or redirect it, rotating it up to 90 degrees in any direction. Any creature the beam passes through completely in this rotation must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 4d8 damage of the beam's type.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you do not use your action to maintain or redirect the beam, the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, fire, lightning, force</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 3 rounds</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Fire" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_FIRE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental flames. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to fire damage and to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain. The first time you enter another creature’s space on a turn, it takes 1d6 fire damage.</li>
                <li>Any time you are hit by a melee attack, the attacker takes 1d6 fire damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Stone" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_STONE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You solidify into stone. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You are petrified (granting you resistance to all damage).</li>
                <li>Your AC becomes 20.</li>
                <li>You gain 15 temporary hit points. Any remaining temporary hit points fade when the spell ends.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you gain an additional 5 temporary hit points for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Water" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WATER">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental water. Until the start of your next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You can move through the space of other creatures and ignore difficult terrain. The first time you move through a Large or smaller creature on a turn, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Become Wind" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BECOME_WIND">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You become a burst of elemental wind. Until the start of the next turn, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain resistance to lightning damage and bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>You gain a flying speed of 30 feet, can move through the space of other creatures, and ignore difficult terrain, but will fall if you are in the air when the spell ends.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it lasts for 1 additional round for each level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Befuddling Curse" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BEFUDDLING_CURSE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You befuddle a creature’s mind, causing it to believe two similarly-sized objects or creatures it can see have been swapped. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, it believes the two things have been swapped.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each time the creature interacts with, attacks, or is attacked by a swapped target, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the spell on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!-- original spell listed a material component but did not specify what the material was -->
    <element name="Bile Beam" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BILE_BEAM">
        <supports>Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a beam of acid in a line 5 feet wide and 100 feet long, which stops early if it impacts a creature, Large or larger object, or solid surface. If the beam hits a creature, the creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 12d4 acid damage and an additional 4d4 acid damage at the end of its next turn. On a success, it takes half as much initial acid damage and no additional damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature or object is killed or destroyed by the beam, the beam continues until it impacts another creature or object.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast the spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d4 for each level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">acid</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (100-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Binding Curse" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BINDING_CURSE">
        <supports>Occultist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You bind a creature to a point within 5 feet of it, causing glowing chains of light to connect it to that point. For the duration of the spell, if the creature attempts to move away from the point, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be unable to move more than 5 feet away from the point until the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target starts its turn more than 10 feet from the binding point, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be dragged 5 feet toward the binding point.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">something from the target creature—such as blood, hair, or scales—which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blackhole" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLACKHOLE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a miniature black hole at a point within range. An event horizon forms in a 15-foot radius around the point, engulfing anything (including light, sound, and magical effects) in the area.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the black hole appears, each creature within 15 feet of the point must make a Dexterity saving throw to avoid being engulfed. On a success, it can move up to its movement speed out of the event horizon of the black hole. If it cannot move to a safe space outside of the event horizon, it automatically fails the save and is engulfed.</p>
            <p class="indent">An engulfed creature is compressed into the point at the center of the spell, taking 12d12 bludgeoning damage at the start of each of its turns while engulfed. Its speed is 0, and it is blinded, deafened, and restrained while engulfed. As an action, an engulfed creature can attempt to forcibly exit the black hole by making a Strength ability check against your spell save DC. On a success, the creature appears in an empty space at the edge of the event horizon.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any spells, effects, terrain, or items that are not being worn or carried that are engulfed within the event horizon vanish and are destroyed. Magical items of Legendary or Artifact rarity are not destroyed, instead reappearing on the ground where the sphere was when the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the spell persists, all movement away from it while within 120 feet of it is considered difficult terrain. All ranged attacks that pass within 120 feet of it have disadvantage. When a creature starts its turn within 120 feet of the black hole, it is pulled 5 feet toward the black hole. At the start of the caster’s turn, all objects within 120 feet of the black hole that weigh less than 1000 pounds, are not being worn or carried, and are not attached to the ground are pulled 20 feet toward the black hole.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade Mirage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLADE_MIRAGE">
        <supports>Bard, Occultist, Ranger, Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You twist illusions around a melee weapon you are holding. When you cast the spell, and as a bonus action on your subsequent turns for the duration, you can feint with the illusory blades, distracting a creature within 5 feet of you and giving you advantage on the next weapon attack against it before the end of the turn. The spell ends early if you let go of the weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, a creature that can see you can make an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. On a success, it becomes immune to the spell's effects.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade Vortex" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLADE_VORTEX">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You fill the air in a 10-foot radius around you with spinning blades until the start of your next turn. When the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it takes 4d4 slashing damage. Until the spell ends, you have half cover against all ranged attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level higher, the damage increases by 1d4 for each level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">slashing</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spinning top</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blastwave" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLASTWAVE">
        <supports>Spellblade, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unleash a fiery blast of power outward in all directions. Each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 4d8 thunder damage and 4d8 fire damage and is knocked back 10 feet. On a success, it takes half as much and is not knocked back.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blazing Beacon" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLAZING_BEACON">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Warlock, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are bathed in holy light, shedding bright light up to 30 feet and dim light for additional 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any creature that targets you with an attack roll or spell that requires them to see you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, they are blinded until the start of their next turn. A creature with darkvision makes this roll with disadvantage. A creature without eyes automatically passes their saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blizzard" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BLIZZARD">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a howling blizzard of swirling clouds of ice and snow which fills a 30-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered at a point you can see within range. The area becomes heavily obscured and difficult terrain. Any creature that starts its turn within the area or enters it for the first time on its turn must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 6d8 cold damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 6th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold</set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boil Blood" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BOIL_BLOOD">
        <supports>Occultist, Spellblade, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point at a creature that has taken slashing or piercing damage within the last minute and make its blood heat to boiling. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or its blood overheats. At the start of each of its turns, it takes 3d4 fire damage and is crippled with agony, turning all terrain into difficult terrain for it.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 2d4 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bond Item" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BOND_ITEM">
        <supports>Inventor</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch an item weighing no more than 100 pounds and form a link with it. Until the spell ends, you can recall it to your hand as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">If another creature is holding or wearing the item when you try to recall it, it can attempt a Charisma saving throw to retain possession of the item. On a success, the spell ends. The creature makes this save with advantage if it has possessed the item for more than 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Barrier" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BARRIER">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a line of low brambles that erupts from a space on the ground you can see within range. This line is 30 feet long and 5 feet wide, made up of six 5-foot squares of brambles. Each patch must connect to another patch and be placed on the ground. The bramble patches are difficult terrain and any creature entering a square of brambles takes 4d4 piercing damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, its speed becomes 0 until the end of its turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The brambles wither and die after 1 day if the area isn’t suitable for them to grow. A creature can clear a 5-foot square with 1 minute of labor, or instantly by inflicting at least 5 points of fire damage. The brambles crumble to dust immediately if you cast this spell again.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can create two additional 5-foot squares of brambles for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Binding" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BINDING">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Brambles burst from your hand, lashing out at a target within range. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, it takes 4d4 piercing damage and, if it is Large or smaller, becomes entangled by brambles. While entangled by brambles, it can’t move, but it can free itself as an action (taking no additional damage) or rip itself free using half of its movement and taking an additional 2d4 piercing damage. On a success, it takes half as much damage and isn't entangled by brambles.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, both the initial damage and the damage taken ripping free of the brambles increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">piercing</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Brilliant Blade" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BRILLIANT_BLADE">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You brandish the weapon used in this spell’s casting, holding it aloft as it flashes with brilliant light. Each creature within 20 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature is blinded until the end of your next turn. On a success, it is blinded until the end of your current turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">blind</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon worth at least 1 sp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burial Barrage" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURIAL_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Spellblade, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You unearth five heavy chunks of earth or stone and hurl them at targets within range. You can hurl them at one target or several. Make a ranged spell attack for each hurled object. On a hit, a target takes 1d12 + 1 bludgeoning damage, and if it is Large or smaller, falls prone. Attacks made as part of this spell have advantage against prone targets, and ignore disadvantage for making a ranged attack against a prone target farther than 5 feet away.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can hurl one additional object for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burn" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURN">
        <supports>Druid, Occultist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Melee</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You ignite a brilliant flame around your hand that sears anything you touch. Make a melee spell attack against a creature or object within range. On a hit, the target takes 1d12 fire damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d12 when you reach 5th level (2d12), 11th level (3d12), and 17th level (4d12).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Burning Strike" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_BURNING_STRIKE">
        <supports>Paladin, Ranger, Spellblade</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a weapon or a piece of ammunition, imbuing it with licking flames. The next time you attack with the empowered item, it bursts into brilliant fire. On a hit, the target takes an additional 4d4 fire damage and begins to burn. On a miss, the target takes half as much damage and does not start to burn. A burning target sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet, and takes 1d4 fire damage at the end of each of its turns. The target or another creature within 5 feet can use an action to extinguish the flames.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you target a weapon with the light property, you can immediately make a single weapon attack with it as part of the same action as casting the spell. Once you make one attack with the targeted item, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, both the initial and ongoing burn damage are increased by 1d4 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ammunition or a weapon worth at least 1 cp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>

<!-- 
<element name="Spell Name" type="Spell" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_SPELL NAME">
        <supports>supports</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">level</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">range</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->