<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Flying Sword Technique for Spellblade</name>
        <description></description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spellblade-flyingsword.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/spellblade-flyingsword.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Flying Sword" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD">
        <supports>spellblade-tech</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a Flying Sword Spellblade, you master the art of the floating blade, separating your willpower from your physical body. Your sword is not just a weapon, but an extension of your mind and a manifestation of your arcane prowess.</p>
            <p class="indent">Born out of a deep understanding of telekinesis and arcane manipulation, your technique combines mental acuity with martial mastery. Whether a reclusive hermit who honed this art in the solitude of your own thoughts, or a prodigy who has broken the conventional boundaries of weapon use, your chosen path is an unorthodox mix of intellect and combat prowess.</p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_FLYING_SWORD" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SWORD_FLIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_BARRAGE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_ULTIMATE_MOVE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_FLYING_SWORD" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_SURGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SWORD_FLIGHT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_BARRAGE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_ULTIMATE_MOVE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Flying Sword Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <p>You learn the following spells at the following levels. The following are Spellblade spells for you, but do not count against your spells known.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Spellblade Level</td><td>Spells Learned</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>jump</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>dancing object</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>fly</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>quicksilver steps</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>animated objects</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP" level="3" spellcasting="Spellblade" prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DANCING_OBJECT" level="5" spellcasting="Spellblade" prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" level="9" spellcasting="Spellblade" prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_QUICKSILVER_STEPS" level="13" spellcasting="Spellblade" prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" level="17" spellcasting="Spellblade" prepared="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Flying Sword" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_FLYING_SWORD">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, during a long rest you can touch a melee weapon, infusing it magical power. This Flying Sword can be carried or stowed like a normal weapon, or you can ready it, causing it to float beside you. While an Flying Sword is readied, you can make attacks with it as part the Attack action, sending it out to strike a target.</p>
            <p class="indent">Attacks made with your Flying Sword are considered melee weapon attacks with the weapon, but you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls, and you can make this attack against a target out to a range of 30 feet away from you. If the weapon has the heavy or special property, this range is halved to 15 feet; and if the weapon has the light property, this range is doubled to 60 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spells infused into the flying weapon affect the target of the attack, but only have a range equal to the range of the spell. If you attack a target beyond the range of the spell, the spell fails and is lost.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>during a long rest you can touch a melee weapon, infusing it magical power. This Flying Sword can be carried or stowed like a normal weapon, or you can ready it, causing it to float beside you. While an Flying Sword is readied, you can make attacks with it as part the Attack action, sending it out to strike a target.
            Attacks made with your Flying Sword are considered melee weapon attacks with the weapon, but you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls, and you can make this attack against a target out to a range of 30 feet away from you. If the weapon has the heavy or special property, this range is halved to 15 feet; and if the weapon has the light property, this range is doubled to 60 feet.
            Spells infused into the flying weapon affect the target of the attack, but only have a range equal to the range of the spell. If you attack a target beyond the range of the spell, the spell fails and is lost.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Phantom Sword" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_SURGE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain a new option for your Arcane Surge:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When you make an attack with your flying sword, you can spend an Arcane Surge to make two phantom copies of it that strike other targets within range. The phantom swords use their own attack rolls. On hit, the target takes damage equal to your Flying Sword’s weapon damage (including modifier) as force damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Arcane Surge (Phantom Sword)">
            <description>When you make an attack with your flying sword, you can spend an Arcane Surge to make two phantom copies of it that strike other targets within range. The phantom swords use their own attack rolls. On hit, the target takes damage equal to your Flying Sword’s weapon damage (including modifier) as force damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sword Flight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_SWORD_FLIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, your mastery of telekinetic manipulation of your blade is so complete you can command it remotely and even use it as a mode of transport. You can stand on your sword to treat it as a Broom of Flying, though only you can ride it, and anything being carried by it is dropped if you attack with it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, the range of your Flying Sword attacks are doubled.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can stand on your sword to treat it as a Broom of Flying, though only you can ride it, and anything being carried by it is dropped if you attack with it.
            Additionally, the range of your Flying Sword attacks are doubled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Phant Sword Barrage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_PHANTOM_SWORD_BARRAGE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 15th level, when you use your Phantom Sword Surge ability, you can create 2 additional copies of your sword (up to 4 total), each of which can strike a different targets within range.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if you use any other use of your Arcane Surge, you can create a single phantom sword copy on your next attack before the end of your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use your Phantom Sword Surge ability, you can create 2 additional copies of your sword (up to 4 total), each of which can strike a different targets within range.
            Additionally, if you use any other use of your Arcane Surge, you can create a single phantom sword copy on your next attack before the end of your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ultimate Move" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLADE_FLYINGSWORD_ULTIMATE_MOVE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 20th level, master the ultimate move of your style unleashing massive power in an unstoppable strike. As an attack as part of the Attack action, you charge your with sword mystical power before sending it forward in a burst of power. All creatures in 120-foot long, 15-foot wide line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 6d6 slashing damage and 6d6 force damage. On success, they take half as much damage. You can exclude a number of creatures from the area of effect equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the sword was infused with spell that has an area of effect through Spellstrike when you made this attack (for example fireball), the spells area of effect becomes the area of effect of this ability (otherwise the spell is discharged against the first target, treating a failed save as a Spellstrike hit).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>As an attack as part of the Attack action, you charge your with sword mystical power before sending it forward in a burst of power. All creatures in 120-foot long, 15-foot wide line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 6d6 slashing damage and 6d6 force damage. On success, they take half as much damage. You can exclude {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures from the area of effect.
            If the sword was infused with spell that has an area of effect through Spellstrike when you made this attack (for example fireball), the spells area of effect becomes the area of effect of this ability (otherwise the spell is discharged against the first target, treating a failed save as a Spellstrike hit).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>