<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Astral Guardian Bond for Warden</name>
        <description></description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="warden-astralguardian.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/KibblesTasty-elements/refs/heads/main/Compendium/warden-astralguardian.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Astral Guardian" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN">
        <supports>warden-bond</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Embarking on a path less traveled, the Astral Guardian Warden transcends the earthly plane and draws from the power of the infinite planes. Touched by the enigmatic forces of space and energy, they embody the mystery of the universe, controlling spatial distortions and manipulating celestial energies.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_ARMS" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_SIXTH_SENSE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_INNATE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_INTERDICTION" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_BEACON" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_GUARDIAN" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_RIFT" />
            <div element="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_PROJECTION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_ARMS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_SIXTH_SENSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_INNATE_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_INTERDICTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_STRIKE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_BEACON" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_GUARDIAN" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_RIFT" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_PROJECTION" level="17" />
        </rules>
        <spellcasting name="Astral Guardian" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false">
            <list>Astral Guardian</list>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Arms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_ARMS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to form up to two astral arms as a bonus action. These are natural melee weapons with the Light property which deal 1d4 force damage on hit. You can additionally use them to grapple creatures and make unarmed strikes with them. You can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls made with these weapons.</p>
            <p class="indent">These arms last until you fall unconscious or you dismiss them as a bonus action. The maximum number of arms you can form increases to 4 at 9th level, and 6 at 17th level. The number of arms do not affect the number of attacks you can make, but the arms can be used to grapple creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make a single unarmed strike or grapple check with one of your Astral Arms as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to form up to 2 astral arms as a bonus action. These are natural melee weapons with the Light property which deal 1d4 force damage on hit. You can additionally use them to grapple creatures and make unarmed strikes with them. You can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls made with these weapons.
            These arms last until you fall unconscious or you dismiss them as a bonus action.
            When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make a single unarmed strike or grapple check with one of your Astral Arms as a bonus action.</description>
            <description level="9">You gain the ability to form up to 4 astral arms as a bonus action. These are natural melee weapons with the Light property which deal 1d4 force damage on hit. You can additionally use them to grapple creatures and make unarmed strikes with them. You can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls made with these weapons.
            These arms last until you fall unconscious or you dismiss them as a bonus action.
            When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make a single unarmed strike or grapple check with one of your Astral Arms as a bonus action.</description>
            <description level="17">You gain the ability to form up to 6 astral arms as a bonus action. These are natural melee weapons with the Light property which deal 1d4 force damage on hit. You can additionally use them to grapple creatures and make unarmed strikes with them. You can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls made with these weapons.
            These arms last until you fall unconscious or you dismiss them as a bonus action.
            When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make a single unarmed strike or grapple check with one of your Astral Arms as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sixth Sense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_SIXTH_SENSE">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 1st level, you gain a special sense allowing you to sense extraplanar energies. You can detect if you are being watched through magic or by creatures within 30 feet of you in the ethereal plane if your passive Perception is equal to or higher than 10 + their CR (or their spell save DC if they are using a spell to observe you).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can detect if you are being watched through magic or by creatures within 30 feet of you in the ethereal plane if your passive Perception is equal to or higher than 10 + their CR (or their spell save DC if they are using a spell to observe you).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Innate Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_INNATE_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally when you select this bond, you gain access to several innate magical abilities by channeling the power of your primal connection.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain the following spells at the listed levels, and can cast each spell once without components or spell slots. Once you cast the spell in this way, you cannot cast it again until you complete a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for these spells. You can cast a spell again before completing a long rest by spending 1 + the level of the spell Endurance Dice.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warden Level</td><td>Innate Spells (1/Long Rest each)</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>detect magic</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>arcane conduit</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>misty step</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>ghost step</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>dimension cutter</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>dimension door</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast each spell once without components or spell slots. Once you cast the spell in this way, you cannot cast it again until you complete a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for these spells. You can cast a spell again before completing a long rest by spending 1 + the level of the spell Endurance Dice.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="1" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="3" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_ARCANE_CONDUIT" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="5" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="9" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_GHOST_STEP" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="13" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_SPELL_DIMENSION_CUTTER" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Astral Guardian" level="17" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Dimensional Interdiction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_INTERDICTION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, the difficult terrain of your Primal Interdiction affects flying creatures within range as well. Additionally, any creature that attempts to teleport into or out of the radius of your Primal Interdiction must succeed a Charisma saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your proficiency bonus. On a failed save, the teleport is wasted and they are not transported. You can choose to allow a creature to teleport in or out of Primal Interdiction without making a save.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>the difficult terrain of your Primal Interdiction affects flying creatures within range as well. Additionally, any creature that attempts to teleport into or out of the radius of your Primal Interdiction must succeed a Charisma saving throw with a {{dimensional-interdiction:dc}} DC. On a failed save, the teleport is wasted and they are not transported. You can choose to allow a creature to teleport in or out of Primal Interdiction without making a save.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dimensional-interdiction:dc" value="8" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="dimensional-interdiction:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <stat name="dimensional-interdiction:dc" value="proficiency" />

        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 3rd level When you expend an Endurance Die, you can empower your next attack with your Astral Arms before the end of your next turn. The attack gains a reach equal to the range of your Primal Interdiction, and if it hits, deals additional damage equal to one of your Endurance Dice.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, you can force the target to make a Charisma saving throw with a DC of 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your Proficiency bonus. On a failure, you can teleport them to an empty space within range of your Primal Interdiction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you expend an Endurance Die, you can empower your next attack with your Astral Arms before the end of your next turn. The attack gains a reach equal to the range of your Primal Interdiction, and if it hits, deals additional damage equal to one of your Endurance Dice.
            Additionally, you can force the target to make a Charisma saving throw with a {{dimensional-interdiction:dc}} DC. On a failure, you can teleport them to an empty space within range of your Primal Interdiction.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Beacon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_BEACON">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, as bonus action, you can teleport a willing creature within 60 feet into any empty space within range of your Primal Interdiction. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all uses when you complete a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, your Primal Interdiction is always considered as in range of allied creature’s teleport abilities, even if it would normally be out of range of the teleport, as long as they are within 300 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
            <description>As bonus action, you can teleport a willing creature within 60 feet into any empty space within range of your Primal Interdiction.
            Additionally, your Primal Interdiction is always considered as in range of allied creature’s teleport abilities, even if it would normally be out of range of the teleport, as long as they are within 300 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dimensional Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_DIMENSIONAL_GUARDIAN">
        <description>
            <p>Additionally at 7th level, you gain resistance to force damage, and advantage on any saving throw against being teleported or moved between planes against your will.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain advantage on any saving throw against being teleported or moved between planes against your will.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FORCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Rift" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_RIFT">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, as an action, you can open an Astral Rift connecting two places with a tear in reality. One rift appears in an empty space within 5 feet of you of your choice, and the other appears in an empty space at a point you are familiar with within a number of miles equal to your Warden level. The tear takes the shape of a swirling opaque roughly circular portal with a 5 foot radius. A willing creature that passes through it is teleported to an empty space within 5 feet of the other portal.</p>
            <p class="indent">The rift remains open for 1 minute once opened, or until you close it as an action. Once you create an astral rift, you cannot do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>ou can open an Astral Rift connecting two places with a tear in reality. One rift appears in an empty space within 5 feet of you of your choice, and the other appears in an empty space at a point you are familiar with within {{level:warden}} miles. The tear takes the shape of a swirling opaque roughly circular portal with a 5 foot radius. A willing creature that passes through it is teleported to an empty space within 5 feet of the other portal.
            The rift remains open for 1 minute once opened, or until you close it as an action. </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Projection" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles' Compendium of Legends and Legacies" id="ID_KTH_COLAL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_ASTRALGUARDIAN_ASTRAL_PROJECTION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, you can astrally project your soul out of your body as an action. When you do so, your body becomes stunned and incapacitated, but you can act in your astral form. While in your astral form, you have the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Astral Form.</strong> Your astral form is resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
                <li><strong>Flying Speed.</strong> You gain a flying speed equal to your movement speed, and can hover.</li>
                <li><strong>Ethereal.</strong> You can pass through physical objects and creatures as if they are difficult terrain, but cannot end your turn inside another creatures or objects’ space, being moved to the last unoccupied space you occupied if you try.</li>
                <li><strong>Planar Shift.</strong> You can move between your current plane and the ethereal plane as an action. While on the ethereal plane, you can see and hear the plane you originated from, which is cast in shades of gray, and you can’t see anything there more than 60 feet away.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Otherwise, your astral form shares all abilities and statistics with your normal form. While you use this ability, your Primal Interdiction projects from your astral form instead of your body. When you use this ability, you can project yourself to any plane or location you are familiar with. If your astral form is reduced to 0 hit points, you are returned to your body and regain 1 hit point. You can end the project at any time as a bonus action, returning to your body.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can astrally project your soul out of your body as an action. When you do so, your body becomes stunned and incapacitated, but you can act in your astral form.
            Astral Form. Your astral form is resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.
            Flying Speed. You gain a flying speed equal to your movement speed, and can hover.
            Ethereal. You can pass through physical objects and creatures as if they are difficult terrain, but cannot end your turn inside another creatures or objects’ space, being moved to the last unoccupied space you occupied if you try.
            Planar Shift. You can move between your current plane and the ethereal plane as an action. While on the ethereal plane, you can see and hear the plane you originated from, which is cast in shades of gray, and you can’t see anything there more than 60 feet away.
            Otherwise, your astral form shares all abilities and statistics with your normal form. While you use this ability, your Primal Interdiction projects from your astral form instead of your body. When you use this ability, you can project yourself to any plane or location you are familiar with. If your astral form is reduced to 0 hit points, you are returned to your body and regain 1 hit point. You can end the project at any time as a bonus action, returning to your body.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>